-保罗·威沃!-是的，先生。
- Paul Weevo! - Yes, sir.
-能听到我说话吗?-是的，阿奇先生。
- Can you hear me? - Yes, sir, Mr. Archie.
-你能找到洞吗?-是的，先生，很多。
- Can you find the holes? - Yes, sir. Lots of them.
那你一定要买大的。
Well, make sure you get the big ones.
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
愉快大叔，你没事做吗?
Uncle Pleasant, ain't you got nothing to do?
什么都没有。
Not a thing.
-你不打算帮他吗?-我退休了。
- Ain't you going to help him? - I'm retired.
娃娃。
Baby Doll.
嘘嘘嘘。
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
阿奇·李，你真是一团糟。
Archie Lee, you're a mess.
你知道他们怎么称呼这种人吗?
Do you know what they call such people?
偷窥!
Peeping Toms!
这是我的房子!
This is my house!
难道没有一个女人是为了远离丈夫而睡在婴儿床上的吗?
And there's no name for a woman that sleeps in a baby's crib to stay away from her husband?
现在我要用口香糖把墙上的洞堵上。
Now I'm gonna plug up the hole in that wall with chewing gum.
如果我哪天抓到你捅…再捅一刀在我睡梦中偷窥我，我要搬进棉花王酒店。
And if I ever catch you pokin' a... a knife through it again to peek at me in my sleep, I'm movin' into the Cotton King Hotel.
你能不能，别让你那些肮脏的老狗碰我的家具?
And would you, please, keep your filthy old dogs off my furniture?
让我和你谈谈。
Let me talk with you.
-听着，我想要…-省省吧。
- Now, listen, I wanna have... - Spare your breath.
留着给你那破轧棉机招揽生意吧。
Save it to drum up some business for your broken-down cotton gin.
把门关上，我好穿衣服。
And close that door so I can get into my clothes.
去吧，穿上你的衣服……除非你到那扇门的另一边把我们之间的门关上。
Go on, just get into your clothes... Not till you get on the other side of that door and close it between us.
今天是11月5日，明天是11月6日，再后天是11月7日。
Today is the fifth day of November, tomorrow's the sixth day of November, and the day after that is November 7.
你知道那是什么日子吧?
And you know what day that is, don't you?
11月7日是你20岁生日。
November 7 is your 20th birthday.
你还记得真是太好了?
Ain't that sweet of you to remember?
我的生日礼物呢?
Where's my birthday present?
哦，你会收到生日礼物的。
Oh, you'll get your birthday present.
如果你没有忘记我们之间的协议，那将在那天到期。
Providing you haven't forgotten the agreement between us, which comes due on that day.
哦，协议?
Oh, the agreement?
是啊，协议。
Yeah, uh-huh, the agreement.
你对着《圣经》发誓要守住这一方。
Which you swore on a Bible to keep your side of.
只要你能保住你的。
Providin' you kept yours.
我有没有碰过你，自从我们…是啊，越频繁越好，还被扇了耳光…有我吗?有我吗?我曾经，曾经，曾经强迫过你成为你的丈夫吗?
Have I ever laid hands on you since we've been... Yeah, as often as possible and gotten slapped off... Have I? Have I? Have I ever, ever, ever once forced myself on you as your husband by law?
难道律法对你毫无意义吗?
Or don't the law mean nothing to you?
你那边的协议呢?
How about your side of the agreement?
你追求我的时候，说得太大了，大人物。
You talked big, mighty big when you was courting me, bigshot.
你跟我爸说要把我安置在全县最豪华的房子里。
You told my daddy you was gonna put me in the grandest house in the county.
我把你放在虎尾监狱了。是我买的，我把你放在里面。
Well, I put you in Tiger Tail. I bought it and I put you in it.
虎尾是全县最宏伟的房子。
And Tiger Tail is the grandest house in the county.
是啊，你让我去了虎尾监狱，整个三角洲最大的破地方。
Yeah, you put me in Tiger Tail, the biggest old wreck of a place in the whole delta.
你跟我爸说你要把这地方恢复到多宾家以前的样子，只会更好。
You told my daddy you was gonna restore this place exactly like it was when the Dobines owned it, only better.
“做个展示的地方，”你说。是啊，怪胎秀。
"Make a show place," you said. Yeah, a freak show.
屋顶上有个男孩。
I've got a boy on the roof right now.
我的人已经在屋顶上了。
I've got my man on the roof now.
你没听到锤子敲屋顶的声音吗?
Can't you hear the hammer on the roof?
那是锤子吗?我还以为那是特大白蚁呢。
Is that a hammer? Why, I thought that was a king-size termite.
混蛋，如果你不是最忘恩负义的小…我已经抵押了自己来满足你的要求。
Doggone, if you ain't the most ungrateful little... I have mortgaged myself to satisfy your demands.
为了得到我，你对我爸爸撒了一大堆谎。
You told a mouthful of lies to my daddy in order to get me.
得到你吗?我还没抓到你。
Get you? I ain't got you yet.
哦，你也不会这么做的。
Oh, and you ain't about to either.
现在我告诉你，如果理想即走即付家具公司把这五套完整的家具从这所房子里搬走，那么这个协议
Now I'm telling you that if the Ideal Pay As You Go Plan Furniture Company removes those five complete sets of furniture from this house, then that agreement
你刚才说的自动取消了。
you just spoke about is automatically cancelled.
现在你能回自己房间去吗?
And now would you kindly go back in your own room?
我今天在城里的时候要找份薪水不错的工作。
I'm gonna get me a good-payin' job while I'm in town today.
只是以防万一。只是以防万一。
Just in case. Just in case.
对着镜子欣赏自己。
Admirin' yourself in the mirror.
你看看你自己。
You just look at yourself.
阿奇·李·梅根，你可不是一个年轻女孩的梦想成真。
You're not exactly a young girl's dream come true, Archie Lee Meighan.
有一个叫乌鸦奶奶的老女巫。
There was an old witch named Granny Crow.
她吐的地方，寸草不生。
Wherever she spit, no grass would grow.
阿奇·李，那个老巫婆肯定吐在你头上了。
That old witch must have spit right on the top of your head, Archie Lee.
谢谢，谢谢。
Thank you, thank you.
你不是女人。你是个未成熟的女人，所以我会体谅你的。
You're not a woman. You're a woman not grown, therefore I'll make allowances.
每次电话一响，萝丝·康弗姨妈就尖叫。
Aunt Rose Comfort screams every time that phone rings.
哦，她为什么要做那样的蠢事?
Oh, why does she do a fool thing like that for?
她说电话铃声让她害怕。
She says phone ringing scares her.
萝丝阿姨，你为什么不接电话?
Aunt Rose, why don't you answer the phone?
-萝丝阿姨!-我发誓。
- Aunt Rose! - My word.
阿姨玫瑰!
Aunt Rose!
玫瑰阿姨安慰!
Aunt Rose Comfort!
萝丝阿姨康弗，你为什么不回答?
Aunt Rose Comfort, why don't you answer?
我喘不上气了，阿奇·李。
I can't catch my breath, Archie Lee.
电话把我吓了一跳。
Phone give me such a fright.
回答这个问题!
Answer it!
喂?我是罗斯·康弗·麦考克尔小姐。
Hello? This is Miss Rose Comfort McCorkle speaking.
不，房子的女主人是阿奇·李·梅根太太，我过世哥哥的女儿……现在他们不想知道了。现在是谁在说话?
No, the lady of the house is Mrs. Archie Lee Meighan, daughter of my brother who passed away... Now they don't wanna know that. Now who is it talking?
-他们想要什么?-我听不太清楚。
- And what do they want? - I don't hear very well.
请你说大声一点好吗?
Would you, please, speak a little louder?
哦，理想的即走即付计划?
Oh, the Ideal Pay As You Go Plan?
-是的…-把电话给我。
- Yeah... - Give me that phone.
这是什么，孩子?
Now what is this, boy?
是的。今天好吗?
Yeah. Today?
不，你得再给我点时间。
Oh, no, you've got to give me a little more time.
嗯，你知道，我最近在生意上遇到了一点挫折……辛迪加种植园建立了他们自己的轧棉机我失去了他们的生意。
Well, you see, I've had a little setback in business lately... Well, the Syndicate Plantation built their own cotton gin and I've lost their trade.
我还需要点时间才能恢复过来。
Well, it's gonna take me a little more time to recover from that.
那就把它拿出来!
Then take it out!
把它拿出来，拿出来，拿出来!
Take it out, out, out!
你再也别想要我的生意了。不,决不!
You'll never get my business again. No, never!
阿奇·李，亲爱的，你们不会失去你们的罚款…你能闭嘴，回厨房去吗?
Oh, Archie Lee honey, you all aren't gonna lose your fine... Would you shut up and get on back in that kitchen?
还有，你在电话里听到的话，一个字也别跟我妻子说，如果你听到一个字的话。
And don't you speak a word that you heard on this phone, if you heard a word, to my wife.
别再在这屋里嚷嚷了。
Don't holler no more in this house.
别再咯咯笑了。
Don't cackle no more.
我保证，我会帮你收拾行李的。我会帮你收拾行李，把你送到日落街的乡下家。
I guarantee, I'll pack you up. I'll pack you up and haul you off to that county home at Sunset.
你说什么，阿奇·李?
What did you say, Archie Lee?
你对我说什么了吗，阿奇·李?
You say something to me, Archie Lee?
是的。
Yeah.
-我说射击!——哦。
- I said shoot! - Oh.
这次是什么让她大叫?
What made her holler this time?
我怎么知道是什么让那个老妇人这一次，最后一次，或者下次大叫?
How do I know what made that old woman holler this time or last time or the next time she hollers?
她上次大吼大叫是因为你朝她扔了东西。
Last time she hollered was 'cause you throwed somethin' at her.
我扔给萝丝阿姨什么安慰?
What did I ever throw at Aunt Rose Comfort?
一杯水，在厨房里唱教堂赞美诗。
A glass of water and for singing church hymns in the kitchen.
水吗?为什么，这么多水。
Water? Why, this much water.
我几乎没洒在她身上。
I barely sprinkled her with it.
-她什么都没听到。-我知道。
- She don't hear nothing. - I know.
-你…-你总得做点什么来引起那个老太太的注意，不是吗?
- Well, you... - Well, you gotta do something to get the old woman's attention, don't you?
是的。嗯?
Yeah. Huh?
-嘿，嘿，放我下来。-拿上你的…让你的…让你的…-把手拿开!——哦!
- Hey, hey, put me down. - Get your... Get your... get your... - Get your hands off me! - Oh!
-脱下来!——哦!
- Take them off! - Oh!
我…我…下次你再违背我们的协议我就搬去棉花王酒店，就下次。
I'm... I'm... I'm moving to the Cotton King Hotel the very next time you try to break our agreement, the very next time.
娃娃!
Baby Doll!
哦，如果你要和我一起进城，你就过来吧。
Oh, you come on down here if you're going into town with me.
我十分钟前就得去看医生了。
I gotta be at the doctor's ten minutes ago.
娃娃!
Baby Doll!
如果你这么没耐心，就先走吧。
If you're so impatient, just go ahead without me.
去吧!不用你，我也有很多办法去市中心。
Just go ahead! I've got plenty of ways of getting downtown without you.
这是事实。
That's the truth.
你来吧!
You come on!
你把你的棉花尾巴拿下来。
You get your cotton-picking tail down here.
慢慢来。
Take your time.
-早上好，山姆。——女士。
- Morning, Sam. - Ma'am.
那你还在等什么?
Well, what are you waiting for?
来吧，上车吧。
Oh, now come on, get into the car.
我会坐到那艘散船的后座等你下车，像个绅士一样给我开门。
I will get into the backseat of that scatter boat when you get out and walk around and open the door for me like a gentleman.
如果你是在等这个，那你得等很长时间了。
Well, you're gonna wait a long time if that's what you're waiting for.
好吧，我敢说，我父亲会在坟墓里翻来覆去。
Well, I declare, my father would turn over in his grave.
我从未见过你父亲下车为任何女人打开车门尤其是你那摇摇晃晃的母亲。
I never once saw your father get out and open the car door for any woman and especially not your waddle-legged mother.
现在上车吧!
Now get on in!
嘿,Sid !来这里!
Hey, Sid! Come here!
-嘿，希德，过来——啊。
- Hey, Sid, come here. - Ughh.
-我们为什么要停在这里?-你在这里做什么?
- What are we stoppin' here for? - What are you doing here?
瓦卡罗现在让我为他工作了。
Well, Vacarro's got me working for him now.
为他吗?你为他工作?
For him? You're working for him?
我还能做什么?辛迪加把我的杜松子酒关了。
What else could I do? Syndicate shut my gin down tight.
-怎么回事?-哦，这是个派对。
- What's going on? - Oh, it's a party.
某种庆祝活动。
A celebration of some kind.
辛迪加为什么不庆祝?
Why shouldn't the Syndicate celebrate?
这里的生意在全县都有。
It's got every last bit of business in the county.
包括我过去得到的每一点和你过去得到的每一点。
Including every last bit of what I used to get and every last bit of what you used to get.
他有最新款的杜松子酒，不像你那堆破酒。
He's got an up-to-date gin, not like that old pile of junk you got.
我们什么时候能离开这里?
When are we gettin' out of here?
你介意动一下你的胳膊吗?
Would you mind moving your arm?
结婚周年快乐。
Happy anniversary.
她真的长大了。
She's sure growed up.
我和你一样喜欢萝丝·康福特阿姨，但我没办法喂你，而且……听着，大人物，哪天罗斯·康瑟姑妈不受欢迎了，
I am just as fond of Aunt Rose Comfort as you are, but I'm in no position to feed and... Now look here, bigshot, the day that Aunt Rose Comfort is unwelcome under your roof,
那我和她都要搬出去。
then her and me both is moving out.
好吧，现在她不会做饭，也不会照顾……如果你不喜欢萝丝·康弗阿姨做的饭，那就给我找个普通仆人。
Well, now she can't cook, she can't take care... Well, if you don't like Aunt Rose Comfort's cookin', then get me a regular servant.
你不会以为我会给你这种又肥又老的人做饭吧。
You don't think that I am gonna cook for a big fat old thing like you.
-别再说老胖子了…-然后你就会变年轻变瘦。
- Quit saying fat old... - Then you get young and thin.
-我就不说老胖子了…——好的。
- And I'll quit saying fat old... - Alright.
但我要通知你。
But I am serving you notice.
如果那个老女人在我的地盘上崩溃死了，我可不想负担丧葬费。
If that old woman breaks down and dies on my place, I ain't gonna get stuck with the funeral expenses.
我要烧死她。他们是这么说的。
I'll have her burned up. Cremated is what they call it.
我会把她的骨灰装在旧可口可乐瓶里然后把瓶子扔进虎尾河口。
I'll pack her ashes in an old Coca-Cola bottle and I'll pitch that bottle into Tiger Tail bayou.
梅根先生，你约会迟到了。
Mr. Meighan, you are late for your appointment.
不管怎样，医生会给你看病的。我不知道为什么。
Doctor's gonna see you, anyway. I don't know why.
哦,嘿。
Oh, hey.
嗯,你好。
Well, hi.
你是牙医吗?
Are you the dentist?
是的，女士，我…我是牙医。
Yes, ma'am, I'm... I'm the dentist.
哦。
Oh.
我在四处找工作，我注意到你的牌子，我想我可以帮你。
Well, I was scoutin' around for a job and I noticed your sign and I thought I might help you out.
约翰，你在做什么?
What are you doing, John?
刚才这里有个男孩，下跳棋赢了我，我还是不明白为什么。
Well, there was a boy in here just a little while ago, beat me at playing checkers, and I still can't figure out why.
好吧，呃，怎么…你会怎么做?
Well, uh, what do... what do you do?
你会打字吗?
Can you type?
——没有。-不，我不打字，但是…我的打印技术真的很好。
- No. - No, I don't do no typin', but, um... Well, I print a real good hand.
我…我不知道我们能不能用这个。
I... I don't know whether we can use that though.
你当牙医太年轻了。
You're awful young to be a dentist.
是的，我只是…我才刚刚开始。
Yeah, I'm just... I'm just getting started.
哦。
Oh.
嗯，你怎么了?
Well, what's the matter with you?
-我有点不对劲，约翰-以什么方式?
- I haven't been myself, John. - In what way?
阿奇·李，你虽然不老，但也不再年轻了。
Well, you know, Archie Lee, you're not an old man, but you're not a young man either no more.
这是事实。这是事实，约翰。这不是谎言。
That's the truth. That's the truth, John. That's no lie.
-你结婚多久了?-差不多一年了。
- How long you been married now? - Just about a year now.
嗯…不过她很漂亮。
Well... She's pretty though.
是的，我想是的。
Yeah, I guess so, hmm.
青春,是吧?
Youth, huh?
你最近压力太大了，是吧?
You've been under some kind of a strain though, ain't you?
不，不，我…一点也不紧张。
No, no, I... no strain at all.
-在我看来你很紧张。
- You look mighty nervous to me.
我不紧张。
I'm not nervous.
嗯，你得会打字。
Well, uh, you'd have to know typin'.
-嗯-在打字
- Mm. - It's typin'.
-很高兴和你谈话。-是的，女士。
- Awfully nice talkin' to you. - Yes, ma'am.
梅根先生，回来。
Mr. Meighan, come back in here.
医生会给你开处方的。
Doctor's gonna give you a prescription.
阿奇·李，我觉得你只需要一点无害的镇定剂。
Archie Lee, all I think you need is some kind of a little harmless sedative.
现在你把这个拿下去给豪格老头，告诉他给你填满，你按照指示去拿。
Now you take this down to old man Hogg and tell him to fill it for you and you take it according to directions.
给你。别忘了你的毛衣。
Here you are. Don't forget your sweater.
这对你的问题一点帮助都没有。
It's not gonna help what's wrong with you one bit.
-你好吗，阿奇?-他知道自己在做什么
- How you doing, Archie? - He knows what he's doing.
-我准备好要走了。-我在大街上坐了差不多一整天。
- I'm ready to go now. - I spent just about the whole day sitting on Main Street.
你怎么不给我带双份蘸酱?
Why didn't you bring me a double dip?
我们还要在这坐多久?
How long are we just gonna sit here?
我得等我的处方。
I gotta wait for my prescription.
-我很无聊。-山姆·希尔有什么好笑的?
- I'm bored. - What the Sam Hill is so funny?
甚至是中国佬。
Even the Chinamen.
大家都知道我们之间的情况。
You know, people know the situation between us.
昨天在Front Street，一个男人对我说:“嘿，Archie Lee，你妻子长得够大了吗?”
Yesterday on Front Street, a man called out to me and said, "Hey, Archie Lee, has your wife outgrowed the crib yet?"
还有三四个人对我唧唧歪歪。
Three or four others haw-hawed at me.
-公开羞辱。——嗯。
- Public humiliation. - Hmm.
私下的羞辱同样令人痛苦。
Private humiliation is just as painful.
世界上没有什么折磨能比得上一个冷酷的女人对一个男人的折磨。
There's no torture on earth to equal the torture which a cold woman inflicts on a man.
没有什么折磨能与之相比。
There's no torture to compare with it.
我所做的一切都是在地狱里监视。
What I've done is staked out a lot in hell.
上面有栋烂房子，还有五套完整的家具没有付款。
A lot with a rotten house on it and five complete sets of furniture not paid for.
你所做的事超出了你的能力范围。
What you done is bit off more than you could chew.
阿奇·李，那是我们的家具吗?
Archie Lee, is that our furniture?
不，不，不，它不是。不。
No, no, no, it isn't. No.
阿奇·李，他们要拿走我们的东西。
Archie Lee, they're taking away our stuff.
你站在那里干嘛?
What are you just standing there for?
宝贝，我得在这等我的处方。
Baby Doll, I gotta wait down here for my prescription.
-你的处方?所有先生!-现在小心。
- Your prescription? Mr. Hannum! - Look out now.
-汉纳姆先生!-过来。
- Mr. Hannum! - Come here.
在他们把剩下的东西拿走之前，我们赶紧回家吧。
Let's get on home before they get the rest of it.
-我要走了。你不…-宝贝娃娃!
- Well, I'm going. Don't you... - Baby Doll!
-你最好去找她?-是啊，我想我最好。
- You better go get her? - Yeah, I guess I better.
-你会怎么做?-对她强硬点。
- What would you do? - Get tough with her.
是的，说起来容易。来吧。
Yeah, easy to say. Come on.
当心，麻烦来了。
Look out, here comes trouble.
-那些人呢，老大?-继续装卡车。
- What about those people, boss? - Just keep loading the truck.
从我的椅子上滚开!从我的椅子上滚开!
Get out of my chair! Get out of my chair!
-走吧，出去!下车!-娃娃。
- Go on, get out! Get off! - Baby Doll.
-他们拿走了我所有的家具!-宝贝娃娃，亲爱的。
- They have all my furniture! - Baby Doll, honey.
你疯了吗?那是我妈妈的灯。
Are you crazy? That's my mama's lamp.
——亲爱的。亲爱的!-放手吧!
- Honey. Honey! - Let it go!
她最好别再打我了。
She better not hit me again.
嘿，把那个放回去!
Hey, you put that back!
我好像听到里面有什么声音。
I thought I heard something rattling around in there.
-娃娃。-让我一个人待在这里。
- Baby Doll. - Leave me alone in here.
我不想和一个让我住在没有家具的房子里的男人共处一室。
I don't wanna be in the same room with a man that would make me live in a house with no furniture.
哦,亲爱的。
Oh, honey.
如果我爸爸知道…他会在坟墓里翻来覆去的。宝贝娃娃，如果你爸爸在坟墓里翻来覆去像你说的那样频繁，那老人会把墓地翻得粉碎的。
My daddy would turn over in his grave if he knew... Baby Doll, if your daddy turned in his grave as often as you say he turned in his grave, that old man would plow up the graveyard.
现在看看你的罗斯阿姨。
Now look at your Aunt Rose.
听着，她在院子里摘玫瑰就像什么都没发生过一样。
Look, she's out there picking roses in the yard as if nothing at all happened in here.
我要搬去棉花王酒店。
I'm moving to the Cotton King Hotel.
我要搬到棉花王酒店。
I am moving to the Cotton King Hotel.
我要找份高薪的工作。
I'm gonna get me a good-payin' job.
棉花王酒店的经理帮我抬了爸爸的棺材。
The manager of the Cotton King Hotel helped carry my daddy's coffin.
-他会给我的。-谢谢你，女士。
- He'll give me one. - Thank you, ma'am.
现在你觉得你能做什么工作?
Now what sort of work do you think you could do?
我可以在美容院卷头发。
I could curl hair in a beauty parlor.
哈哈，我觉得我可以当个女主人。
Ha-ha, I reckon that I could, uh, be a hostess.
二楼已经安全了。
Second floor's all clear now.
对从一个地方走来的人微笑。
Smile at people coming in a place.
-什么地方?-任何地方。
- What place? - Any place.
我可以当，呃，收银员。
I could be a, uh, cashier.
哦，现在你不能数零钱了。
Oh, now you can't count change.
我可以，呃，分发菜单或者程序之类的。
Well, I could, uh, pass out menus or programs or something.
-向人们问好。-哦，现在，宝贝娃娃…嗯，我可以打个招呼。
- Say hello to people. - Oh, now, Baby Doll... Well, I can say hello.
在这里签字。
Sign here.
哦，棉花王?我是梅根太太。
Oh, Cotton King? This is Mrs. Meighan.
我想订一个明天早上的房间。
I wanna reserve a room for tomorrow mornin'.
我想用我的娘家姓，娃娃卡森·麦科克尔。
And I want to register under my maiden name which is Baby Doll Carson McCorkle.
我爸爸是tc·卡森·麦科克尔。
My daddy was T.C. Carson McCorkle.
去年夏天我结婚时他去世了。
He died last summer when I got married.
他是棉花王酒店经理非常亲密的朋友。
And he was a very close personal friend of the manager of Cotton King Hotel.
你知道的。
You know.
他叫什么名字?
What's his name?
阿奇·李，看看这些花。
Archie Lee, look at these flowers.
自然之诗。
Poems of nature.
嗯，嗯，嗯，嗯。
Hmm, hmm, hmm, hmm.
阿奇先生，我们什么时候再轧棉花?
When we gonna gin out some more cotton, Mr. Archie?
哦,亲爱的。
Oh, dear.
哦,我的。
Oh, my.
这是我喝过最浓的白兰地水。
That's the stoutest brandy water to ever wet my whistle.
它一定是从虎尾河口出来的。
It must have come right out of Tiger Tail bayou.
年轻人，瓦卡罗先生，今晚你在这里举办了一个非常棒的派对来庆祝你成为辛迪加种植园和杜松子酒的经理一周年。
Young man, Mr. Vacarro, this is a mighty fine party you are throwing here tonight in honor of your first anniversary as the manager of the Syndicate Plantation and Gin.
等一下，孩子，按住。
Just a minute there, sonny, hold it down.
我有件事想说出来。
I got a little something I ought to get off my chest.
别忘了你的观点。
Don't forget your point.
-我们的好邻居欣赏…-等一下，孩子
- Us good neighbors appreciate... - Oh, just a second, son.
先生们，一则通告。
Gentlemen, an announcement.
周六晚上有鱼苗派对。
There'll be a fish fry Saturday night.
鲶鱼，油炸玉米饼，跳舞，带上你的女人。
Catfish, hush puppies, dancin', bring your ladies.
哦，你去吧，先生。
Oh, you go right on, sir.
我只是想让你知道，我们的好邻居很欣赏你的成就，在老虎尾县这片神圣的土地上收获了有史以来最大的棉花收成。
I just want you to know that us good neighbors appreciate your achievement in bringing in the biggest cotton crop that ever was picked on this blessed soil of Tiger Tail county.
参议员，我老爸曾经说过"无话可说又不被说服说出口的人是有福的"
Hey, senator, my old dad once said, "Blessed is he who has nothing to say and cannot be persuaded to say it."
那边有几个男孩看起来不太高兴。
Couple of boys there don't look too happy with it.
他们没有理由这么做。你让他们破产了。
They got no reason to be. You put them out of business.
伙计，那边有很多好酒。
Man, they got plenty good liquor over yonder.
我自己喝。
I'll drink my own.
你刚来的时候，我承认我们这些老家伙有点冷淡。
Now when you first came here, I'll admit that us old-timers were a bit standoffish.
一开始我们不太了解你。
We didn't know you all that well at first.
自然地，一件事对某些人有利，对另一些人却无益。
Naturally, a thing is profitable to some is unprofitable to others.
就像那家伙说的，一个人的美食可能是另一个人的毒药。
As the fella says, one man's meat is another man's poison.
我们都知道，在某种程度上，由于这个人在辛迪加种植园的成功，这里的一些人在经济上遭受了损失，但作为一个整体，社区将获得丰厚的利润。
We all know that some folks here have suffered financially due in some measure to this man's success with his Syndicate Plantation, but as a whole, the community stands to reap a nice fat profit.
嘿，参议员，下次为共和党竞选吧。
Hey, senator, next time run on a Republican ticket.
我们会帮你争取到黑鬼的选票。
We'll get the nigger vote out for you.
-席尔瓦!席尔瓦先生!——火!
- Silva! Mr. Silva! - Fire!
-席尔瓦先生!-席尔瓦!席尔瓦先生!
- Mr. Silva! - Silva! Mr. Silva!
-席尔瓦!席尔瓦先生!-席尔瓦!
- Silva! Mr. Silva! - Silva!
把马车挪开!移动它们!
Move the wagons! Move them!
让棉花动起来!摇滚!
Get that cotton moving! Rock!
罗克，让棉花动起来!把马车弄出来!
Rock, get the cotton moving! Get those wagons out!
席尔瓦先生，你在哪里?
Mr. Silva, where are you?
煤油。
Kerosene can.
好吧，法警，你打算怎么找到那个烧了我杜松子酒的人?
Alright, marshal, what you gonna do about finding the man that burned down my gin?
你凭什么确定你的杜松子酒被人放火烧了?
Well, what makes you so sure your gin was set fire to?
哦，看看周围。
Oh, look around.
你见过这么多快乐的脸吗?
Did you ever see so many happy faces?
这看起来像一个富人的葬礼，他所有的亲戚都参加了。
It looks like a rich man's funeral with all his relations attending.
我可不想证明这一点。
I'd hate to have to prove that.
我可不想靠你来证明。
I'd hate to have to depend on you to prove it.
我真的无法想象。
I can't honestly imagine.
如果是纵火案，是谁干的?
If it's a case of arson, who done it?
大火发生的时候，所有被你弄丢生意的人都在那辆杜松子酒里。
Every poor man you put out of business was right there in that gin when the fire broke out.
一个不是。我知道有一个不是。
One wasn't. I know of one that wasn't.
孩子，说出听起来可疑的名字是件冒险的事。
Boy, namin' names that sounds suspicious is risky business.
我没有指名道姓。但看起来凶手忘记把这个带走了。
I didn't name a name. But looks like whoever did it forgot to take this with him.
法警，作为你的副手，我会拿走这个罐子仔细检查。
Marshal, as your deputy, I'll take this can and I'll examine it very carefully.
看看有没有证据证明这是用来纵火的。
See if there's any basis for thinking it was used for starting a fire.
为了得到这个易拉罐，我不惜血本，我一定要留下它。
I had to run through fire to get this can and I mean to keep it.
把它锁在皮卡车里。
Lock it in the pickup truck.
嘿，吉娜，给我们唱首歌。
Hey, Gina, sing us a song.
我不会的
* I shall not *
我不会被感动的
* I shall not be moved *
我不会的
* I shall not *
我不会像树一样被移动
* I shall not be moved like a tree *
那是种在水边的
* That's planted by the water *
我不会被感动的……＊
* I shall not be moved... *
你打算怎么把剩下的棉花轧出来?
Hey, what you gonna do about ginning out the rest of your cotton?
我用卡车把它运到日落街。
I'll truck it over to Sunset.
柯林斯会帮我弄清楚的。
Collins will gin it out for me.
柯林斯有自己的棉花，伙计。
Collins got his own cotton to gin, fella.
那我就把它运到玻利瓦尔县。
Well, then I'll truck it over to Bolivar county.
这里没人会帮我找借口的。
Ain't nobody around here's gonna gin it out for me.
我不会被感动的
* I shall not be moved *
*每条路线都走得更高?＊
* Every route go higher? *
席尔瓦!
Silva!
——摇滚!-滚开…摇滚，不，不，这是…是我，洛克。
- Rock! - Get off... Rock, no, no, it's... it's me, Rock.
-他们有罐子，老大——什么?什么?
- Oh, they got the can, boss. - What? What?
——谁?谁?-我不知道。
- Who? Who? - I don't know.
肯定是某个人。从后面猛扑过来。
It was somebody. Jumped me from the rear.
退后，退后。
Just stay back, stay back.
孩子，听我这个土生土长的老前辈的建议吧。
Boy, take the advice of an old-timer who was born and raised in this county.
认识方圆五十英里内的每一个黑鬼，每一条猎犬每一个毒菌和每一个树桩。
Knows every nigger, every hound dog every toadstool and every tree stump for 50 miles around here.
我劝你不要再无理取闹了。
My advice is for you not to make any more reckless charges.
当然，作为一个外国人，你已经被一振和二振了……我不需要建议，不需要法律，不需要法庭。
Of course, you being a foreigner, you already got strike one and strike two... I want no advice, no law and no court in this county.
我来自一个非常古老的国家，那里的传统是每个人都要做出自己的判断。
I come from a very old country where it's tradition for each man to make his own justice.
就像私酿的酒，私密，秘密。
Like bootlegged liquor, private, in secret.
因为那里也有腐败。
Because there was corruption there too.
如果正义被执行，那也是由每个人自己单独执行的。
And if justice was executed, it was executed by each man himself, alone.
我指的是圣经中的正义。
I mean biblical justice.
以眼还眼，以牙还牙。
Eye for eye, tooth for tooth.
走吧，洛克。
Let's go, Rock.
不要注意这个。我必须这么做。
Don't notice this. I got to.
我什么也没注意到。
I hadn't noticed a thing.
-是谁干的，洛克?-你知道的。
- Which one did it, Rock? - You know.
他们都在小屋里，除了一个。
They were all there in the shed, all except one.
不在场的那个，我以为是他干的。
The one who wasn't there, I figured he did it.
他是帮我榨棉花的人。
Well, he's the one who's gonna gin out my cotton.
扶她起来。
Get her up.
家具今天要搬回来。
The furniture's coming back today.
-发发慈悲吧。-快，快，快。
- Have mercy. - Come on, get, get.
什么也别说。
Don't say a word.
有只小鸟已经告诉我你会把那几车棉花直接送到我家门口我想让你知道，你是个非常幸运的家伙。
A little bird already told me that you'd be bringing those wagons full of cotton straight to my door and I want you to know that you're a very lucky fella.
如何来吗?
How come?
我的意思是，我可以保留其他订单，给你优先权。
I mean that I'm in a position to hold back the other orders and give you a priority.
好吧，来吧。快点，从卡车里出来。
Well, come on. Come on, get out of that truck.
-和我一起喝杯咖啡。-你的价格是多少?
- And have some coffee with me. - What's your price?
现在你记得我的价格了。它没有改变。
Now you remember my price. It hasn't changed.
你的设备怎么样?这一点也没有改变吗?
How about your equipment? That hasn't changed either?
A1的形状，一直都是。现在你应该记住这一点。
A1 shape, always was. Now you ought to remember that.
我记得你需要一个新的锯筒。你有吗?
I remember you needing a new saw cylinder. You got one?
好吧,我……我还没在市场上找到能和旧的一样好的。
Well, I... I can't find one on the market to equal the old one yet.
来吧，来吧，和我一起喝杯咖啡。
Come on, come on, have some coffee with me.
我们都准备好了。
We're all ready for you.
我猜当你昨晚看到我的杜松子酒被烧成灰烬时，你一定想到明天早上你可能会得到一大笔生意。
I guess when you saw my gin burnin' down last night, you must have figured you might get a good deal of business thrown your way in the morning.
你想知道吗?
You wanna know something?
我总是很乐意知道一些事情当有事情需要知道的时候。
I'm always glad to know something when there's something to know.
我昨晚没看到你的火。
I never did see that fire of yours last night.
不，先生，不，先生。
No, sir. No, sir.
来吧。来我家喝点咖啡吧。
Come on. Come on in my house and have some coffee.
现在，你，你也来。来吧，来吧，伙计。
Now, you, you come too. Come on, come on, man.
不，先生，我昨晚没看到你的火。
No, sir, I never did see that fire of yours last night.
我们一吃完晚饭就上床睡觉了，直到早上吃早饭的时候我才知道你的轧棉机烧坏了。
We hit the sack right after supper and I didn't know until breakfast time this morning that your cotton gin burned down.
哦，宝贝娃娃，出来。
Oh, Baby Doll, come out here.
到这里来。过来，娃娃。
Come here. Come here, Baby Doll.
我要你过来见见辛迪加种植园的瓦卡罗先生。
I want you to come right over here and meet Mr. Vacarro from the Syndicate Plantation.
你叫什么名字，瓦卡罗?
Say, what's your first name, Vacarro?
-席尔瓦。-怎么拼?
- Silva. - How do you spell it?
资本S-I-L-V-A。
Capital S-I-L-V-A.
果然吗?就像一线希望?
Sure enough? Like a silver linin'?
嗯，黑暗中总有一线希望。
Well, every cloud has got a silver linin'.
这是什么，《圣经》里的?
Oh, what's that from, the Bible?
不，是鹅妈妈的书。
No, the Mother Goose book.
那个名字听起来很陌生。
That name sounds foreign.
是的，梅根太太。
It is, Mrs. Meighan.
我是那个经营辛迪加种植园的德国佬。
I'm known as the wop that runs the Syndicate Plantation.
不要骂自己。
Don't call yourself names.
让其他人骂你吧。
Let the other folks call you names.
你真是个幸运的家伙，席尔瓦。
Well, you sure are a lucky fella, Silva.
镀金甚至镀镍。
Gold or even nickel-plated.
你真幸运，我现在能接你这种身材的活。
Oh, you sure are lucky that I could take a job on of your size right now.
你看，你是我最近的邻居，我相信睦邻政策。
You see, you're my closest neighbor and I believe in the good neighbor policy.
你帮了我一个忙我也帮了你一个忙，瓦卡罗先生。
You do me a good turn and I do you a good turn, Mr. Vacarro.
以牙还牙是我们赖以生存的政策。
Tit for tat and tat for tit is the policy we live on.
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
阿姨玫瑰。玫瑰阿姨安慰。
Aunt Rose. Aunt Rose Comfort.
哦，宝贝娃娃。娃娃。
Oh, Baby Doll. Baby Doll.
宝贝，让你爸爸的老处女姐姐给瓦卡罗先生端一壶新咖啡。
Baby, get your daddy's old maid sister to bring out a fresh pot of coffee for Mr. Vacarro.
-自己去找她?——亲爱的。
- Get her yourself? - Honey.
亲爱的，亲爱的，亲爱的。
Honey, honey, honey.
现在我要你取悦这些先生们。
Now I want you to entertain these gentlemen.
噢,看。看，看，看。
Oh, look. Look, look, look, look.
哦，看她的脸红。看。
Oh, look at her blush. Look.
看看她的脸红。哦，这是我的宝贝。
Look at her blush. Oh, this is my Baby.
哦，这是我的小女儿。
Oh, this is my little girl.
她的每一分珍贵都是我的。
Every precious ounce of her is mine.
Bluh-bluh。Muah。
Bluh-bluh. Muah.
阿姨玫瑰!玫瑰阿姨安慰!
Aunt Rose! Aunt Rose Comfort!
请原谅我打哈欠。我们昨晚睡得很晚。
Excuse my yawn. We was up awful late last night.
这么说你是德国人?
So you're a wop?
不，我是西西里人，梅根太太。
No, I'm a Sicilian, Mrs. Meighan.
一个非常古老的民族。
A very ancient people.
——这一切。-不，姐姐。西西里。
- Shis. - No, Sis. Sicilian.
我来自科珀斯克里斯蒂。
I'm from Corpus Christi.
哦，真不寻常。
Oh, how unusual.
亲爱的，中午，我要你带瓦卡罗先生去棉花王酒店吃鸡肉晚餐。
Honey, at noon, I want you to take Mr. Vacarro in town to the Cotton King Hotel for a chicken dinner.
签上我的名字。
Sign my name.
只有当你倒霉的时候，瓦卡罗先生，你才会发现谁是你的朋友我要证明这一点。
You know, it's only when bad luck hits you, Mr. Vacarro, that you find out who your friends are and I mean to prove it.
宝贝娃娃，我要你在家里招待这位先生。
Baby Doll, I want you to entertain this gentleman in the house.
这是睦邻政策。
It's a good neighbor policy.
俗话说得好，以牙还牙。
Tit for tat and tat for tit as they say.
你帮了我一个忙，我也帮了你一个忙，没错。
You do me a good turn and I do you a good turn some time in the future, that's right.
来吧。来吧，宝贝娃娃。来吧。
Come on now. Come on, Baby Doll. Come on.
现在让马车动起来。让他们动起来。
Now make those wagons move now. Get them rollin'.
在那房子里谁都不舒服。
Can't make nobody comfortable in that house.
比如你能不能找到一把椅子坐下。
Like if you can find a chair to sit down on.
你要咖啡吗?
You want coffee?
不，只是一杯凉水。谢谢你，女士。
No, just a cool drink of water. Thank you, ma'am.
好吧，家里的水是暖的。
Oh, well, the house water runs warm.
但如果你有精力使用那边的旧水泵，你可以从那个水箱里给自己弄到一杯清凉的饮料。
But if you got the energy to work that old pump over there, you can get yourself a nice cool drink from that there cistern.
我有精力燃烧。
I got energy to burn.
把他们的垃圾倒在院子里。
Dump their garbage in the yard.
无知、放纵和恶臭。
Ignorance and indulgence and stink.
我觉得年轻的梅根太太闻起来很香。
I thought that young Mrs. Meighan smelled pretty good.
你把鼻子贴在棉花上。
You keep your nose to the cotton.
水有时来，有时不来。
Sometimes water comes, sometimes it don't.
好吧，这次会的。
Well, this time it will.
请给我一杯清凉可口的井水。
Bring me a drink of that nice cool well water, please.
“这么说你是德国人?”
"So you're a wop?"
我的手臂已经没有力气从井里打水了。
I don't have the strength anymore in my arm that I used to to draw water out of that well.
你想喝杯凉水吗?
Would you like a cool drink of water?
你好!我是Rose Comfort McCorkle阿姨。
How do you do? I'm Aunt Rose Comfort McCorkle.
我哥哥是宝贝娃娃的爸爸，tc·卡森·麦科克尔先生。
My brother was Baby Doll's daddy, Mr. T.C. Carson McCorkle.
我一直来这里，自从…嗯，我现在想不起来是什么时候。
I've been visiting here since, uh... Well, just now I can't remember just when it was since.
我希望你不介意用葫芦喝水。
I hope you don't mind drinking out of a gourd.
哦。谢谢你！
Oh. Thank you.
打扰一下。那只老母鸡弗斯又回到我厨房了。
Excuse me, please. That old hen Fuss has got back in my kitchen again.
我还能想出更糟的办法来打发一下午给梅根太太送清凉的井水呢。
Why, I could think of worse ways to spend an afternoon delivering cool well water to Mrs. Meighan.
你守着棉花，听到了吗?
You stay with the cotton, you hear?
继续，继续用棉花。
Go on, stay with the cotton.
在水中有这样的区别。
There's such a difference in water.
你可能不这么认为，但确实有。
You wouldn't think so, but there certainly is.
我猜你在这里住的时间不长，梅根太太。
I take it you've not had this place long, Mrs. Meighan.
不，我们的时间不长。
No, we ain't had it long.
虎尾路没有收垃圾的人吗?
Don't you have garbage collectors on Tiger Tail Road?
哦，好吧，好吧，他们来这里要多花点钱，而阿奇·李……哦，我不知道。有时我几乎要放弃了。
Oh, well, well, it costs a little bit extra for them to come out here and Archie Lee... Oh, I don't know. I almost give up sometimes.
你是说这房子里有一堆没有家具的房间吗?
Did I understand you to say you've got a bunch of unfurnished rooms in this house?
五套完整的家具被理想的随走随付家具公司运走。
Five complete sets of furniture hauled away by the Ideal Pay As You Go Plan Furniture Company.
你什么时候遭遇这种不幸的?
When did this misfortune fall upon you?
昨天。
Yesterday.
那不是很可怕吗?昨天。
Ain't that awful? Yesterday.
我们俩在同一天遭遇了不幸。
Both of us had misfortunes on the same day.
——嗯?-你的家具丢了。
- Hmm? - You lost your furniture.
-我的轧棉机烧了。-是啊。
- My cotton gin burned down. - Oh, yeah.
-太巧了。-那是什么?
- Quite a coincidence. - What's that?
我说这是不幸的巧合。
I said it was a coincidence of misfortune.
哦，当然。
Oh, well, sure.
我是说，一堆没有家具的房间你能做什么?
I mean, what can you do with a bunch of unfurnished rooms?
我们可以玩捉迷藏。
Well, we could play hide and seek.
不是我。我不擅长运动。
Not me. I'm not athletic.
是啊，当我来到这个县接手辛迪加种植园的管理时，这房子是空的。
Yeah, well, when I arrived in this county to take over the management of the Syndicate Plantation, this house was empty.
-我听说那里闹鬼。-是啊，那里闹鬼
- I was told it was haunted. - Oh, yeah, it was haunted.
这就是为什么阿奇·李几乎不花一分钱就得到了它。
That's why Archie Lee got it for almost nothin'.
有时我不知道该去哪里，该做什么。
Sometimes I don't know where to go or what to do.
嗯，这并不罕见。
Well, that's not uncommon.
人们没有受过教育就来到这个世界。
People enter this world without instruction.
——嗯?-我说…这是你的早餐吗，梅根太太?
- Hmm? - I said... Is that your breakfast, Mrs. Meighan?
我说，人们来到这个世界上，没有人告诉他们该去哪里，该做什么。
I said people come into this world without instruction of where to go or what to do.
所以他们徘徊了一会儿，然后就走了。
So they wander a little and then go away.
漂移一会儿，然后消失。
Drift for a while and then vanish.
所以要为新人腾出空间。
And so make room for newcomers.
Old-goers,新人。
Old-goers, newcomers.
来来回回。
Going and coming, back and forth.
冲,冲。
Rush, rush.
永久的,什么都没有。
Permanent, nothing.
什么生活……持续的时间足以让你认真对待它……
Anything living... that lasts long enough to take it serious...
这是什么?
What's this?
这是那辆旧的皮尔斯-阿罗汽车，是多宾太太的，她曾经是这栋房子的主人，现在还在这里出没。
This is that old Pierce-Arrow car, belong to Mrs. Dobine, the lady that used to own this house and haunts it now.
去哪里，夫人?
Where to, madam?
哦，我们要扮演司机。
Oh, we're gonna play chauffeur.
好的，再见。
Yeah, goodbye now.
开车带我去河边开着所有的窗户让我凉快点。
Hey, drive me along the river with all the windows open to cool me off.
司机坐在前座。
The chauffeur sits in the front seat.
前座没有靠垫。
The front seat's got no cushion.
哦,是的。
Oh, yeah.
来吧，伙计们!站起来，我们走!
Come on, men! Get on your big feet, let's go!
-来吧!-哦，我们来轧棉花吧。
- Come on! - Oh, let's gin some cotton.
-小心，伙计们!-站起来。
- Look out, men! - Get on those big feet.
我们进去吧。
Let's get in here.
哦，让我们剪一些棉花吧。
Oh, let's cut some cotton.
自从理想的随走随付计划家具公司失去耐心后，很难找到一个舒适的地方坐下……当理想出现时，你很难舒服地坐着
It's hard to find a place to sit since the Ideal Pay As You Go Plan Furniture Company lost patience, to sit in comfort... It's hard to sit in comfort when the Ideal
现付现付的人会失去耐心……你的杜松子酒烧尽了。
Pay As You Go Plan people lose their patience... and your gin burns down.
-你能把腿挪一下吗?-但这里很凉快。
- Would you move your leg? - But it's cool here.
坐起来很舒服。
Comfortable to sit in.
-这是什么?-那是我的魅力手镯。
- What's this here? - That's my charm bracelet.
我爸爸给我的。
My daddy gave it to me.
这就是十诫。
Them's the Ten Commandments.
-这些呢?-我的生日。
- And these here? - My birthdays.
你过了多少个迷人的生日?
How many charming birthdays have you had?
手镯上有多少魅力就有多少。
As many as there are charms on the bracelet.
-你介意我…-数一数。
- Do you mind if I... - Count them.
十五，十六，十七，十八，十九。
Fifteen, sixteen, seventeen, eighteen, nineteen.
这是所有。
That's all.
明天我就20岁了。
I'll be 20 tomorrow.
明天是选举日，也是我的生日，也是富兰克林·德拉诺·罗斯福先生第一次当选的日子。
Tomorrow is election day and my birthday and the day that Mr. Franklin Delano Roosevelt was elected for his first term.
这对国家来说是伟大的一天，原因有二。
It's a great day for the country for both reasons.
他是个值得尊敬的人。
Oh, he was a man to respect.
你是位值得尊敬的女士，梅根太太。
Well, you're a lady to respect, Mrs. Meighan.
我吗?不。
Me? No.
我连四年级都没读完。
I never got past the fourth grade.
你为什么辞职?
Why'd you quit?
我在长除法上遇到了很多麻烦。
Well, I had a great deal of trouble with long division.
是吗?
Yeah?
老师会让我到黑板前做长除法的一道题，我就会走到黑板前，把头靠在黑板上，哭啊哭啊哭。
The teacher would send me up to the blackboard to work on a problem in long division and I would go up to the blackboard, lean my head against it and just cry and cry and cry.
你能把腿挪一下吗?
Would you move your leg?
你想移动我的腿吗?
Do you wanna move my leg?
是啊，否则我出不去。
Yeah, otherwise I can't get out.
好的。
Okay.
嗯…我就一直哭啊哭啊。
Well... I would just cry and cry and cry.
最后，我离开了学校……哦，一个没有受过教育的女孩就是一个没有教育的女孩…
Well, finally, I left school and... Oh, a girl without education is a girl without edu...
Vacarro先生吗?
Mr. Vacarro?
我只是来买些山核桃。
Just picking up a few pecan nuts.
哦，不好意思。
Oh, excuse me.
不好意思，瓦卡罗先生，我可不想吃一个人在嘴里咬碎的坚果。
Excuse me, Mr. Vacarro, but I wouldn't dream of eating a nut which a man had cracked in his mouth.
你有很多优点。
You've got many refinements.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
现在我觉得你不用担心长除法的失败了。
Now I don't think you need worry about your failure at long division.
毕竟，你通过了短除法。
After all, you got through short division.
短间隔是所有女士都该应付的。
Short division's all a lady ought to be called on to cope with.
是的。
Yeah.
我现在该进去了。
Well, I ought to be going in now.
哦。
Oh.
但每次看到那么多空房间，我都很沮丧。
But I get so depressed going through all them empty rooms.
所有的房间都是空的吗?
All the rooms empty?
除了育儿室和厨房。
All except for the nursery and the kitchen.
房间里的东西都是花钱买的。
The stuff in them rooms is paid for.
你有个孩子在托儿所吗?
You have a child in the nursery?
我吗?不。
Me? No.
我自己也睡在育儿室。
I sleep in the nursery myself.
我把板条放在婴儿床上。
I let the slats down on the crib.
你为什么睡在育儿室?
Why do you sleep in the nursery?
瓦卡罗先生，这是个私人问题。
Mr. Vacarro, that's a personal question.
我现在该进去了。
Well, I ought to be going in now.
但你知道，那房子里有些房间我从没去过。
But you know, there are rooms in that house that I never been in.
比如，阁楼。
Like, for instance, the attic.
你知道大多数时候我都不敢一个人进那栋房子。
You know that most of the time I'm scared to go in that house by myself.
就像昨晚火灾发生的时候。
You take like last night when the fire broke out.
我在这里坐了好几个小时，好几个小时，好几个小时，等着阿奇·李回家，因为我害怕自己一个人进屋。
I sat here for hours and hours and hours waiting for Archie Lee to come home because I was scared of going in the house by myself.
没有你丈夫的照顾，你一定很害怕。
Well, it must have been scary without your husband to look out for you.
哦，我告诉你。
Oh, I'm telling you.
大火爆发了，整个天空都被疯狂的影子照亮了。
The fire broke out and lit up the whole sky with crazy shadows.
我们家里也没有可乐。
And we didn't have a Coke in the house.
我在生阿奇·李的气。
Oh, I was mad at Archie Lee.
你生梅根先生的气。关于什么?
You were mad at Mr. Meighan. What about?
他走了，把我留在屋里，可乐也没喝。
He went off and left me without a Coke in the house.
离开了…没有可乐，是吗?
Went off and left... Without a Coke, did he?
是的，他说了。当然了。
Yes, he did. He certainly did.
直到火灾发生很久之后他才回来。
And he didn't get back until way after the fire had broken out.
我的眼睛里，鼻子里，喉咙里都是烟。哦。
And I had got smoke in my eyes, in my nose, in my throat. Ooh.
噢，我当时太紧张了，我哭了。
Oh, I was in such a worn out nervous condition, I cried.
最后，我吃了两茶匙止痛药。
Finally, I took two teaspoons of paregoric.
听起来你昨晚过得很不舒服。
Sounds like you passed a very uncomfortable night.
哦，听起来怎么样?
Oh, sounds like?
哦，是的。
Ooh, it was.
你说梅根先生晚饭后就不见了。
So Mr. Meighan, you say, disappeared after supper.
嗯?
Huh?
你说梅根先生晚饭后离开了一段时间?
You say Mr. Meighan left the house for a while after supper?
哦，是的，有一会儿。
Oh, yeah, for a moment.
就一会儿，嗯?
Just for a moment, huh?
一分钟有多长?
How long a moment?
你想说什么，瓦卡罗先生?
What are you driving at, Mr. Vacarro?
开车吗?
Driving at?
是的，你看我的眼神很好笑。
Yes, you're looking at me so funny.
你还记得他消失了多久吗，梅根太太?
How long a moment did he disappear for, can you remember, Mrs. Meighan?
哦，这有什么区别?
Oh, what difference does it make?
我是说，这跟你有什么关系…你为什么要介意我问呢?
I mean, what does it matter to you... Why should you mind my asking?
你说得好像我在受审似的。
You make it sound like I'm on trial for somethin'.
你不喜欢假装自己是目击证人吗?
Don't you like to pretend like you're a witness?
什么证人，瓦卡罗先生?
Witness of what, Mr. Vacarro?
比如说，一起纵火案。
Oh, say, for instance, a case of arson.
纵火是什么?
What's arson?
故意放火毁坏财产。
The willful destruction of property by fire.
——哦。——什么?
- Oh. - What?
嗯,关于…我丈夫晚饭后离开，我可以解释
Well, about... about my husband leavin' after supper, I can explain that.
-你能吗?-当然可以。
- Can you? - Oh, sure, I can.
嗯,很好。现在你怎么解释呢?
Well, good. Now how can you explain it?
怎么了，梅根太太?你不能集中思想吗?
What's the matter, Mrs. Meighan? Can't you collect your thoughts?
你脑子里一片空白，对吧?
Your mind's a blank on the subject, hmm?
你不记得你丈夫晚饭后为什么失踪了吗?
You find it impossible to remember just what your husband disappeared for after supper?
你无法想象他去做了什么差事，对吧?你能吗?
You can't imagine what kind of errand he went on, can you? Can you?
但当他回来的时候，嗯，让我想想，辛迪加种植园刚刚发生火灾。
But when he returned, well, let's see, the fire had just broken out at the Syndicate Plantation.
瓦卡罗先生，我不知道你想说什么。
Mr. Vacarro, I can't imagine what you could possibly be drivin' at.
没有?
No?
你是个很不称职的证人，梅根夫人。
You're a very unsatisfactory witness, Mrs. Meighan.
好吧，我们该别提这个话题了吗?
Well, should we drop the subject?
-哦，我真希望你能来。-当然。
- Oh, I sure do wish you would. - Well, sure.
为烧坏的杜松子酒哭也没用。
There's no use crying over a burned down gin.
而且，就像你丈夫说的，这个世界是建立在以牙还牙的基础上的。
Besides, like your husband says, this world is built on the principle of tit for tat.
你这话是什么意思?
What do you mean by that?
没有任何明确的承诺。
Nothing specific.
-你介意我…——什么?
- Do you mind if I... - What?
坐下来?
Sit down?
它足够坚固，能支撑我们俩吗?
Is it strong enough to support us both?
嗯，我希望如此。
Well, I hope.
现在让我们摇摆一下，好吗?
Now let's swing a little, huh?
你看起来很紧张。
You seem all tense.
运动使人放松。
Motion relaxes people.
它就像一个摇篮。
It's like a cradle.
摇篮使婴儿放松。
A cradle relaxes a baby.
他们叫你宝贝，不是吗?
They call you Baby, don't they?
哦，那是一种昵称。
Oh, that's sort of a nickname.
在秋千上，你可以像在摇篮里一样放松。
Well, in a swing, you can relax just like in a cradle.
好吧,我……我不喜欢荡秋千。这让我很震惊。
Well, I... I don't like to swing. It shakes me up.
而且，我已经足够放松了。
Besides, I'm relaxed enough as much as necessary.
哦，不，你不是。
Oh, no, you're not.
你神经太紧张了吧?
Your nerves are all tied up, hmm?
-你让我很紧张。-只是和你一起摇摆?
- Well, you make me nervous. - Just swinging with you?
-不，不只是这样。-还有什么?
- No, not just that. - What else then?
你问我的那些关于火灾的问题。
All them questions you asked me about the fire.
我只是想问问你丈夫的情况。
I was only enquiring about your husband.
关于他晚饭后离开家的事。
About his leaving the house after supper.
但我没必要向你解释这些事。
But there's no reason why I should have to explain things to you.
不。
No.
我们应该放松吗?
Should we just relax?
你能挪过去一点，腾出点地方来吗?
Would you move over and make a little room?
那地方够你住吗?
Is that enough room for you?
对我来说足够了。你呢?
It's enough for me. How about you?
你丈夫说得很好。
It was a lovely remark your husband made.
我是说睦邻政策。
The good neighbor policy, I mean.
“你帮我一个忙，我也帮你一个忙。”
"You do me a good turn and I do you one."
他是这么说的。
That was the way he put it.
-好了。——谢谢。
- There now. - Thanks.
有很多细小的棉绒漂浮在空气中。
There's a lot of fine cotton lint floating around in the air.
我知道有。我鼻窦不舒服。
I know there is. It bothers my sinus.
你是个很精致的女人，梅根太太。
Well, you're a very delicate woman, Mrs. Meighan.
精致的?我吗?
Delicate? Me?
你的东西不多，但还有选择。
There isn't much of you, but what there is is choice.
-我可以说很美味。——嗯?
- Delectable, I might say. - Hmm?
你fine-fibered…软……和光滑。
You're fine-fibered... soft... and smooth.
瓦卡罗先生，我们的谈话转向个人了。
Mr. Vacarro, our conversation certainly is taking a personal turn.
你让我想起了棉花。
You make me think of cotton.
不。
No.
没有织物或布料，甚至没有绸缎或丝绸……没有哪种纤维，甚至连棉纤维都没有……拥有绝对细腻的肌肤。
No fabric or cloth, not even satin or silk cloth... and no kind of fiber, not even a cotton fiber... has the absolute delicacy of your skin.
我该怎么说呢?谢谢还是什么?
Well, what should I say? Thanks or something?
不，你笑就行了，梅根太太。
No, you just smile, Mrs. Meighan.
你的笑容很迷人。
You've got an attractive smile.
——酒窝。——没有。
- Dimples. - No.
哦，不，你需要。
Oh, yes, you do.
来吧，笑一笑，梅根太太。
Come on now, smile, Mrs. Meighan.
你看，你有，你有。
There, you see, you do, you do have them.
别碰我。请不要碰我。
Don't touch me. Please don't touch me.
-我不喜欢被碰。-那你傻笑什么?
- I don't like to be touched. - Well, why do you giggle?
因为你让我觉得有点歇斯底里，瓦卡罗先生。
Because you make me feel kind of hysterical, Mr. Vacarro.
-真的吗?-瓦卡罗先生。
- I do? - Mr. Vacarro.
是吗?
Yes?
我…我去弄点柠檬水。
I... I think I'll go and make us some lemonade.
你为什么要那样做?
What did you do that for?
我不想被剥夺和你在一起的快乐。
I don't wanna be deprived of the pleasure of your company.
还没有。
Not yet.
瓦卡罗先生，你真是越来越熟了。
Oh, Mr. Vacarro, you certainly are getting familiar.
难道你没有一点爱玩的精神吗?
Don't you have any fun-loving spirit about you?
这可不好玩。
Well, this isn't fun.
那你还傻笑什么?
Well, why do you giggle then, hmm?
-因为我怕痒。-你怕痒?
- Because I'm ticklish. - You're ticklish?
别那么神经质。
Don't be so skittish.
一个……好吧，那我就起来。
A... alright, I'll get up then.
继续。
Go on.
哦。
Oh.
我觉得很虚弱。
I feel so weak.
哦，我的头很模糊。
Oh, my head is fuzzy.
——模糊?——嗯。
- Fuzzy? - Hmm.
毛茸茸的，嗡嗡作响的。
Fuzzy and buzzy.
我的头在晃荡。
My head is swinging round.
肯定是甩得太厉害了。
Must have been that swinging that done it.
-我胳膊上有东西吗?——没有。
- Is there something on my arm? - No.
哦,然后…-别说了，感觉很好笑。-感觉如何?
Oh, then... - Cut it out, it feels funny. - How does it feel?
上上下下都觉得很好笑。
Oh, it feels funny all up and down.
别换我了，好吗?
Quit switchin' me, will you?
我只是把苍蝇赶走。
I'm just shooing the flies off.
哦，好吧，他们不会伤害什么。
Oh, well, they don't hurt nothin'.
别闹了，不然我要打电话了。
Now cut it out or I'm gonna call.
给谁打电话?
Well, call who?
路上的男孩。
Boy on the road.
好吧，那就打电话吧。
Well, go on, call then.
男孩!
Boy!
你就不能大声点吗?
Can't you call any louder, hmm?
-我觉得…-你就不能大声点吗?
- I feel so... - Can't you call any louder?
我…我觉得很好笑。是什么……-我怎么了?-你只是在放松。
I... I feel so funny. What's... - What's the matter with me? - You're just relaxing.
屈服现在别再反抗了。
Give in. Now stop fighting it.
哦，我不是…我不是在反抗，但是…是你和你对…关于我…我的丈夫…怀疑吗?怀疑如?
Oh, I'm not... I'm not fighting it, but it's... it's you and your suspicions about... about my... my husband... Suspicions? Suspicions such as?
-他烧了你的杜松子酒——好吗?
- That he burned down your gin. - Well?
-他没有。-是吗?
- Well, he didn't. - Didn't he?
不，他没有。
No, he didn't.
他……他……他没有。
He... he... he didn't.
我现在要进屋去。
I'm going in the house now.
你相信有鬼吗，梅根太太?
You believe in ghosts, Mrs. Meighan?
我做的事。
I do.
我相信恶灵的存在。
I believe in the presence of evil spirits.
你说的是什么邪灵?
What evil spirits you talking about?
暴力和狡猾的灵魂，恶毒，残忍，背叛，破坏。
Spirits of violence and cunning, malevolence, cruelty, treachery, destruction.
这只是人类的特征。
Them's just human characteristics.
恶灵出没于人心，占据人心，从一个人的心蔓延到另一个人的心，就像火焰从一片叶子蔓延到另一片叶子
The evil spirits that haunt the human heart and take possession of it and spread from one human heart to another human heart, the way a fire goes springing from leaf to leaf
一根树枝接一根树枝，直到整个森林都被它点燃。
and branch to branch in a tree till the forest is all aflame with it.
你只是脑子着火了。
You just got fire on the brain.
我认为它比表面上看起来的要多。
I see it as more than it seems to be on the surface.
我昨晚看到了那些恶灵的爆炸。
I saw it last night as an explosion of those evil spirits.
我和它搏斗，我冲进去，打它，踩它，对着它喊着上帝的诅咒。
I fought it, I ran into it, beating it and stamping it, shouting a curse of God at it.
他们把我拖了出来，我快要窒息了。
They dragged me out, suffocating.
我被打败了。
I was defeated.
当我躺在地上时，大火已经赢得了战斗，周围是一圈人的身影。
When I came to lying on the ground, the fire had won the battle and all around was a ring of human figures.
我抬头一看，它们被照亮了。
I looked up, they were illuminated.
他们的眼睛，他们的牙齿像这样闪闪发光。
Their eyes, their teeth were shinin' like this.
-对，像这样。-不，不要…不要……-像这样。-请别吓我。
- Yeah, like this. - No, don't... don't... - Like this. - Please don't scare me.
我看到的面孔都在咧嘴笑。
The faces I saw were grinning.
然后我知道，我知道火灾不是意外。
And then I knew, I knew the fire was not accidental.
你也知道这不是偶然的。
And you know it was not accidental too.
这是一种表达，一种需要毁灭的表现。
It was an expression, a manifestation of the need to destroy.
这就是为什么我说我相信鬼魂，在闹鬼的地方，在闹鬼的地方，那些占据他们的人的心被仇恨和毁灭的恶魔占据。
That's why I say I believe in ghosts, in haunted places, in places haunted by the people that occupy them with hearts overrun by demons of hate and destruction.
我相信他住的地方，这栋房子，闹鬼。
I believe his place, this house, is haunted.
阿姨玫瑰!玫瑰阿姨安慰!
Aunt Rose! Aunt Rose Comfort!
这所房子闹鬼。
This house is haunted.
我想我要去后门弄点柠檬水。
I think I'm going around the backdoor and make us some lemonade.
阿奇·李。
Archie Lee.
-阿奇·李?-阿奇·李。
- Archie Lee, huh? - Archie Lee.
我们现在就去找阿奇·李吧。
Yeah, let's go and see Archie Lee now.
阿奇·李。
Archie Lee.
-上面发生了什么?-装置坏了。
- What's going on up there? - Contraption broke down.
你最好离阿奇先生远点。
And you better stay away from Mr. Archie.
他气得要死。
He's fit to be tied.
-卡住了。快点，把扳手给我。
- It's stuck. - Come on, give me the wrench.
来吧，把扳手给我。给……阿奇·李，我有事要告诉你…-你在这里做什么?-你这个大懒汉。
Come on, give me the wrench, man. Give... Archie Lee, I got something to tell you... - What are you doing here? - You big slob.
-你在这里做什么?——你……你把我丢在那里。
- What are you doing here? - You... you left me over there.
我不是告诉过你，有黑鬼在这里工作的时候，千万别来这酒吧吗?
Didn't I tell you never to cross over to this gin when niggers are workin' here?
你知道你给我留下了什么…进展如何，梅根先生?
You know what you left me with... How's progress, Mr. Meighan?
很好，很好，很好。
Fine, fine, great, great.
就我个人而言，我根本听不到杜松子酒的声音。
Personally, I can't hear the gin runnin' at all.
大人物!
Bigshot!
-怎么了?——一文不值。
- What's holdin' up? - Nothin'.
——摇滚吗?-他的锯筒坏了。
- Rock? - His saw cylinder is busted.
它的数据。梅根，我在安装自己的设备前检查了你的设备。
It figures. Meighan, I inspected your equipment before I put in my own.
我还买了自己的轧棉机，因为这些设备都坏了。
And I put up my own cotton gin because this equipment was rotten.
-别紧张…-以前是烂的，现在还是烂的。
- Take it easy... - Was rotten, still is rotten.
现在我的表是两点一刻。
Now it's a quarter past 2:00 by my watch.
你在跑道上有很多车。
You got a lot of wagons out on the runway.
-听着，你们意大利人…-别管我们意大利人了!
- Listen, you Italians... - Never mind about we Italians!
你最好给自己买个新的锯筒，看，让这玩意儿重新运转起来。
You better get yourself a new saw cylinder, see, and get this contraption runnin' again.
如果你在城里买不到，就去罗斯戴尔。
And if you can't get one in town, you go to Rosedale.
如果你在罗斯戴尔买不到，你最好想办法过河，一直开到小石城，但你必须……你再开一次口
And if you can't get one in Rosedale, you better get across the river somehow and keep going right on to Little Rock, but you have to... One more crack out of you
你只能在药店里看到棉花。
and the only cotton you'll see will be in a drugstore.
现在你最好拉，兄弟。
Now you better haul, brother.
他会……他会去罗斯戴尔。
He'll... he'll go to Rosedale.
-我有话要对…-拜托，我不是…哦，我没时间。
- I got something to say to... - Please, I ain't... Oh, I ain't got time.
大人物!大人物!大人物!
Bigshot! Bigshot! Bigshot!
现在这杯杜松子酒…天啊，他又要追她了。
Now this gin... Boy, he's getting her again.
是的，我们的小卖部有一个这样的锯筒。
Yeah, we got a saw cylinder like this in our commissary.
果然。
Sure enough.
去把它拿过来，让汉克帮你把它放进去，让这个装置重新运转起来。
Go get it and bring it here and get Hank to help you put it in and get this contraption runnin' again.
他不会在镇上买新的了。
He's not gonna get a new one in town.
如果他必须过河，就别等他了。
If he has to go across the river, don't wait for him.
岩石…我把皮卡留给你。
Rock... I'll leave the pickup truck with you.
待在房子附近。
Stay close to the house.
待在那儿，等我出来。
Stay there till I come out.
嘿,阿奇。阿奇·李!
Hey, Archie. Archie Lee!
阿奇·李!
Archie Lee!
哦,维…别碰我。请不要碰我。
Oh, d... don't touch me. Please don't touch me.
——哦吼!-罗斯阿姨。
- Woohoo! - Aunt Rose.
玫瑰阿姨安慰。
Aunt Rose Comfort.
我要去县医院看一个重病的朋友。
Gotta go and see a mighty sick friend in county hospital.
哦。
Oh.
你可以对着月亮大喊大叫，也可以对着那个老太太大喊大叫。
You might as well shout at the moon as that old woman.
你不想让她走?
You don't want her to go?
她不能把我一个人留在这里。
Well, she's got no business leavin' me alone here.
但她对巧克力糖果情有独钟。
But she has a passion for chocolate candy though.
她目不转睛地看报纸，看她认识的人有没有在县医院登记过。
She watches the newspapers just like a hawk to see if anybody she knows is registered at the county hospital.
-在医院?-是的。
- At the hospital? - Yeah.
他们……他们在县医院给病人发糖果
They... they pass out candy to the patients at the county hospital, you know.
朋友和…亲戚们会送他们鲜花和糖果。
Friends and... and relatives send them flowers and candy.
萝丝·康弗姨妈去看望他们，吃光了他们所有的巧克力糖果。
Aunt Rose Comfort goes to visit them and eats up all their chocolate candy.
你知道，上个星期，罗斯·康弗姑妈的一位老太太朋友在县医院里快要死了，罗斯·康弗姑妈去看她，吃光了她所有的巧克力糖果。
You know, last week an old lady friend of Aunt Rose Comfort's was dyin' at the county hospital and Aunt Rose Comfort went to visit her and ate up all her chocolate candy.
全部吗?
All of it?
就在那个老妇人快死的时候，她把它吃了。
Right while the old woman was dyin', she ate it up.
哦，我喜欢老人。他们疯了。
Oh, I like old people. They're crazy.
哦。
Oh.
-梅根夫人?——嗯。
- Mrs. Meighan? - Hmm.
你介意我问你一个…私人问题吗?
Do you mind if I ask you a... personal question?
什么，瓦卡罗先生?
What, Mr. Vacarro?
你真的嫁给梅根先生了吗?
Are you really married to Mr. Meighan?
瓦卡罗先生，这是个私人问题。
Oh, Mr. Vacarro, that is a personal question.
所有问题或多或少都是私人问题，梅根夫人。
All questions are more or less personal, Mrs. Meighan.
嗯…看到……-当我…-我结婚的时候，我还没准备好结婚。
Well... See... - When I... - When I got married, well, I wasn't ready for marriage yet.
那时我只有18岁。
I was only 18.
但我爸爸几乎快死了他想在死前看到我被照顾好。
But my daddy was practically on his deathbed and he wanted to see me took care of before he died.
而老阿奇·李已经像条病狗一样四处游荡了很长一段时间。
And old Archie Lee had been hanging around like a sick dog for quite some time.
这里的男孩都很可怜。
And the boys around here are a sorry lot.
他们约你去看电影却带你去了老采石场。
You know, they ask you to the movies and take you out to the old stone quarry instead.
你得下车，朝他们扔石头。
You've gotta get out of the car and throw stones at them.
我在这里遇到过一些男孩如果我告诉你，他们会把你的头发卷起来。
Oh, I've had some experiences here with boys that would just curl your hair if I told you.
我和男孩子们的经历。
The experiences which I've had with boys.
哦,但是……老阿奇·李，你知道，他是个老家伙。
Oh, but... old Archie Lee, you know, he was an older fella.
那时候他的生意比现在好。
Well, his business was better in those days.
嗯，他在轧棉花。
Mm, he was ginnin' out lots of cotton.
那是在你打开轧棉机之前，记得吗?
That's before you put up your cotton gin, you remember?
-是的，我记得。——嗯。
- Yeah, I remember. - Hmm.
我跟我爸说我还没准备好结婚…我爸爸告诉阿奇·李我还没准备好阿奇·李答应我爸爸他会等我准备好。
Well, I told my daddy that I wasn't ready for marriage and... my daddy told Archie Lee that I wasn't ready for it and Archie Lee promised my daddy that he would wait until I was ready.
后来，婚礼推迟了。
Then the marriage was postponed.
哦，不，不是婚礼。
Oh, no, not the weddin'.
我们举行了婚礼。
We had the weddin'.
我爸爸把我送走了。
My daddy gave me away.
是啊，但你说阿奇·李等了?
Yeah, but you said Archie Lee waited?
是啊，婚礼之后，他一直在等。
Yeah, after the weddin', he waited.
为了什么?
For what?
让我做好结婚的准备。
For me to be ready for marriage.
他要等多久?
How long did he have to wait?
哦，他还在等。
Oh, he's still waitin'.
不过我们有个协议。
We had an agreement though.
我告诉他在我20岁生日的时候，我会准备好。
I mean, I told him that on my 20th birthday, I'd be ready.
-那是明天。——嗯。
- That's tomorrow. - Mm-hmm.
还有，呃，我…你准备好了吗?
And, uh, I... will you be ready?
那要看情况了。
Well, that all depends.
在什么?
What on?
家具是否还能回来。
Whether or not the furniture comes back.
我猜。
I guess.
你丈夫比我认识的任何人都出汗多现在我知道为什么了。
Your husband sweats more than any man I know and now I can understand why.
让我想想。
Well, let's see.
好吧，我宣布。
Well, I declare.
我很抱歉。我…在那里。
I'm sorry. I... There.
现在你在这儿等着。
Now you wait right here.
我要做柠檬水，放在门廊上。
I'm gonna make lemonade and serve it on the porch.
-是的，女士，就在这儿。-你在那儿等着。
- Yes, ma'am, right here. - You wait right there.
现在你在那儿等着。
Now you wait right there.
好的，女士，我会等的。
Yes, ma'am, I'll wait.
是的,女士。我就待在这里。
Yes, ma'am. I will stay right here.
是的,女士。
Yes, ma'am.
我总有一天会给自己买辆冷冻机的。
Oh, I'm gonna get me a Frigidaire one of these days.
愚蠢的老东西。
Stupid old thing.
忘记生火了。
Forgot to light the stove.
哦。
Ooh.
Vacarro先生。
Mr. Vacarro.
啊。
Ah.
哦，我的天哪。
Oh, my goodness.
我们马上就能喝柠檬水了。
We'll be having lemonade in a minute now.
嘿，你怎么把漂亮的裙子弄湿了?
Hey, how did you get that pretty dress all wet?
真是一团糟。
What a mess.
瓦卡罗先生，你在那等着。
Mr. Vacarro, now you wait right there.
阿奇·李，是你吗?
Archie Lee, is that you?
需要一些东西。
Needs something.
妈妈米娅。
Mama mia.
啊。
Ah.
*你真丢人，真丢人……＊
* Shame shame shame on you... *
昏死过去,昏死过去!
Giddy-up, giddy-up!
*羞耻，羞耻，为你感到羞耻，洛克希小姐
* Shame shame shame on you Miss Roxy *
为你的所作所为感到羞耻
* Shame shame shame on what you've done *
你让我流汗，让我说话，直到我瘦得皮包骨
* You made me sweat and talk till I was skin and bones *
你让你的爱人悲伤哦，看看现在的我
* You cause your lovers grief oh look at me now *
*羞耻，羞耻，为你感到羞耻，洛克希小姐
* Shame shame shame on you Miss Roxy *
谁在里面?
Who's in there?
为你的所作所为感到羞耻
* Shame shame shame on what you've done *
*为你所做的感到羞耻羞耻?＊
* Shame shame shame on what you've done? *
滚出我的房子…
Get out of my house...
瓦卡罗先生，我知道是你你让我很紧张。
Mr. Vacarro, I know that's you and you're making me very nervous.
啊!
Aah!
噢,噢。哦，是的，我会抓住你的!
Ooh, ooh. Oh, yeah, I'll get you!
啊!
Aah!
哦，啊，哦。
Ooh, ah, oh.
救命，救命，救命，救命!
Help, help, help, help!
哦!
Oh!
哦。
Oh.
打开,芝麻!
Open, sesame!
游戏结束了，我退出。——没有。
- Game's over, I quit. - No.
不，你得一直玩捉迷藏，直到你成功为止。
No, you gotta keep playing hide and seek till you're it.
现在，瓦卡罗先生，请你下楼去好吗我好打开这扇门出来?
Now, Mr. Vacarro, would you, please, go back downstairs so that I can unlock this door and come out?
这个阁楼的情况糟透了。
This attic is in awful weak condition.
你……你想让我叫消防部门在你掉下去的时候带着网来接住你吗?
You... you want me to call the fire department to come here with a net to catch you when you fall through?
哦，不，没有时间了。
Oh, no, there wouldn't be time.
不，我想他们不会准时到的。
No, I don't suppose they'd get here on time.
就像昨晚他们来扑灭烧了我的杜松子酒的火一样。
Any more than they did last night when they come to put out the fire that burned down my gin.
——哦。——嗯?
- Oh. - Hmm?
我告诉你我要怎么做。
I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
现在，我会从门缝里塞进铅笔和纸只要你在纸上签名。
Now, I'm gonna slip a pencil and paper under this door and all I want is your signature on the paper.
什么纸?
What paper?
你可以称之为法律宣誓书证明阿奇·李·梅根烧了辛迪加的杜松子酒。
Oh, you might call it an affidavit legally stating that Archie Lee Meighan burned down the Syndicate gin.
哦。
Oh.
瓦卡罗先生，这层楼…这层楼要塌了…就在我下面。
Mr. Vacarro, this floor... this floor's about to give... give out right under me.
只需要一分钟。好吧，你说呢?
It will just take a minute. Well, what do you say?
好吧，你就把它放在那里，我很乐意签字后寄给你。
Well, you just leave it right there and I'll be happy to sign it and send it to you.
哈!梅根太太，我是西西里人。
Ha! Hey, Mrs. Meighan, I'm a Sicilian.
你知道，我们是一个非常古老的种族，一个古老的种族，而古老的种族天生就不值得信任。
You know, we're a very old race of people, an ancient race, and ancient races are untrustful races by nature.
现在你要么签了这张纸要么我就砸开这扇门。嗯?
Now either you're gonna sign this piece of paper or I'm gonna break this door down. Huh?
你听到了吗?
Do you hear me?
我猜你不相信我。
I gather you don't believe me.
现在你要么同意签字或者我来这里，我的体重增加了…
Now you're either gonna agree to sign this thing... or I'm coming out here and my additional weight...
我该怎么办?
What am I gonna do?
你得照我说的做。
You're gonna do what I tell you.
没有?
No?
-不，别伤害我。-请别说了。
- No, don't hurt me. - Please stop.
我什么都愿意做，只要快点。
I'll do anything, only hurry.
-你想让我做什么?-你要写下你的名字。
- What do you want me to do? - You will write your name.
呃,muah。
Ugh, muah.
去做吧。
Go ahead.
你现在可以出来了。
You can come out now.
需要我在楼梯上的脚步声吗?
Need my descending footsteps on the stairs?
需要我的脚步在…哦，瓦卡罗先生!
Need my descending footsteps on the... Oh, Mr. Vacarro!
你听见我下楼的脚步声了吗?
You hear my descending footsteps on the stairs?
Vacarro先生。
Mr. Vacarro.
好吧，你自由了，我也是，再见。
Okay, you're home free and so am I. Bye-bye.
等等，瓦卡罗先生。你要去哪里?
Oh, wait a minute, Mr. Vacarro. Where are you goin'?
回到我在西部昆西特的灰色小家里去睡个安稳觉。
Back to my little gray Quonset home in the West to take a peaceful siesta.
但我想…我想…
But I want to, uh... I want to, uh...
这就是你想要的…
Is that all that you wanted...
让我承认阿奇·李烧了你的杜松子酒
for me to confess that Archie Lee burned down your gin?
你还能想象什么，梅根太太?
What else did you imagine, Mrs. Meighan?
嗯…
Well...
Meighan太太……
Mrs. Meighan...
你还是个孩子，梅根太太。
You're a child, Mrs. Meighan.
这就是我们玩捉迷藏的原因。
That's why we played the game of hide and seek.
这是孩子们玩的游戏。
It's a game for children.
好吧，你没必要大老远跑回家睡个午觉。
Well, you don't have to go all the way home to take a nap.
你可以在这里打个盹。
You could take a nap here.
我是说，反正也要下雨。
I mean, it's gonna rain anyhow.
家里所有的家具都搬走了。
All the furniture's been removed from the house.
不是育儿室里的东西。
Not the stuff in the nursery.
里面有一张小床，一张婴儿床。
There's a small bed in there, a crib.
你可以蜷缩起来……把板条放下来。
You could curl up... and let the slats down.
我很乐意接受邀请。
I'll be happy to accept the invitation.
上来吧，唱着歌哄我入睡。
Come on up and sing me to sleep.
我爸爸会在坟墓里翻来覆去。
My daddy would turn over in his grave.
——对不起。-哦，快点，快点。
- Sorry. - Oh, come on, now, now.
我可以的。你知道的，我很能干。
I'm good for it. You know, I'm good for it.
-现在我要拿我的…-没有功劳。
- Now I'll take my... - No credit.
如果你不想要，我就把它带到别的地方去!
I'll take it somewhere else if you don't want it!
听着，我爸爸的手表。
Look, listen, my daddy's watch.
——现金。——在这里。
- Cash. - Here.
是他名字的字母，而不是数字?
The letters of his name instead of numbers, huh?
我把这块表留给你。
I'm gonna leave this watch here with you.
——现金。-给他，然后滚出去!
- Cash. - Give it him and get out!
谢谢你，先生。
Thank you, sir.
我米……非常感谢您，先生。
I'm m... much obliged to you, sir.
现在你能把这玩意启动了吗?来吧。
Oh, now will you get this thing going? Come on now.
-来吧，好吗?-闭嘴。
- Come on now, will you? - Shut up.
我们已经尽可能快了。
We're going as fast as we can.
你们肯定很快就修好了。
Hey, you all must have done some mighty fast repairs.
没有维修。装一个新的锯筒。
No repairs. Put in a new saw cylinder.
是的，从哪里来的?
Yeah, from where?
我和老板在我们家喝过一杯。
Boss and I had one at our place.
在我离开这里之前，怎么没人告诉我这个消息呢?
Well, how come I wasn't let in on this bit of information before I lit out of here?
我都快累死了。
I just about killed myself getting that.
那个德国佬瓦卡罗在哪儿?
Where is that wop Vacarro?
我想听听你的解释。Vacarro !
I wanna get some explanation of this. Vacarro!
他在哪里?
Well, where is he?
-你看到老板了吗，诺姆?-不，先生。
- You seen the boss man, Norm? - No, sir.
-你看到老大了吗，慕斯?-不，先生。
- You seen the boss man, Moose? - No, sir.
我的人呢?
Where are my men?
哦，我让他们回家了。
Oh, I sent them home.
我的意思是，它们毫无用处。
I mean, they're useless.
你继续操作。
Well, you keep operating.
嘿!
Hey!
你知道，这不是劣质的杜松子酒。
You know, this isn't a bad old gin.
知道那个人已经走了
* Know the man done gone *
*知道那个人已经回新奥尔良了*
* Know the man done gone back to New Orleans *
现在宝贝请不要走
* Now baby please don't go *
宝贝，请不要走
* Baby please don't go *
宝贝，请不要再回到Rolling Fork
* Baby please don't go not back to Rolling Fork *
因为我把你当娃娃一样对待?＊
* Because I treat you like a doll? *
嘿，有人住在这里吗?
Hey, anybody living here?
有人还住在这房子里吗?
Anybody still living in this house?
呐喊!呐喊!呐喊!
Whoop! Whoop! Whoop!
Blu-blu-blu-blu-blu !
Blu-blu-blu-blu-blu!
我是阿奇·李。
It's Archie Lee.
这里发生了什么?
What happened here?
嗯?我说这里发生了什么?
Huh? I said what happened here?
阁楼上的灰泥破了。
The plaster broke in the attic.
好吧,如何?怎么……-怎么会这样?-事情是怎么发生的?
Well, how? How did... - How did that happen? - How does anything happen?
它就这样发生了。
It just happens.
我不是告诉过你不要在这里溜达吗?
Ain't I told you not to slop around here in a slip?
晚饭快好了。
Supper almost ready now.
光是厨房里的破损就能毁了一个有钱人。
Well, the breakage alone in that kitchen would ruin a well-to-do man.
现在你上楼去，穿上像样的衣服，然后再下来。
Now you go on up and get some decent clothes on and then come back down here.
你知道吗，华盛顿特区有个新分局。
You know, there's a new bureau in Washington DC.
它被称为UW局。你知道UW代表什么吗?
It's called the UW Bureau. You know what UW stands for?
它代表没用的女人!
It stands for useless women!
他们有秘密计划把…
They got secret plans to put the...
把他们关起来枪毙了他们。
to lock them all up and shoot them.
这是什么。
That's what.
他们开枪。
Shoot them.
现在你听到了。我说开枪打他们。
Now you heard me. I said shoot them.
那破坏性的男人呢?
How about men that's destructive?
难道他们没有什么计划来围捕破坏性的人然后枪毙他们吗?
Ain't they got some plan to round up destructive men and shoot them?
你说的是什么破坏性的男人?
What destructive men you talking about?
那些把东西炸了，烧了东西的人，因为他们太邪恶，太愚蠢，否则就无法相处。
Men that blows things up and burns things down 'cause they're too evil and too stupid to get along otherwise.
因为他们的竞争对他们来说太激烈了，所以他们变成了罪犯。
'Cause their competition is too much for them so they turn criminal.
他们做纵火之类的事。
They do things like arson.
故意放火毁坏财产。
The willful destruction of property by fire.
谁跟你说的?
Who said that to you?
嘿，看看门廊上有什么。
Hey, look what's up there on the porch.
把门廊的灯打开。路上有男人……现在别管了。谁……谁跟你说纵火了?
Put up the porchlight. There's men on the road... Never mind now. Who... Who said arson to you, huh?
谁说的…这种蓄意破坏?
Who spoke of this... This willful destruction?
为什么，你从来不知道这些词。谁跟你说的?
Why, you never knew them words. Who said them to ya?
有时候，大人物，你好像一点都不相信我有多聪明。
Sometimes, bigshot, you don't seem to give me credit for very much intelligence at all.
我上过学，还是个杂志读者。
I've been to school in my life, and I'm a magazine reader.
谁吹的口哨?
Who gave that whistle?
你们谁对我老婆吹了狼哨?
Which of you give a wolf whistle at my wife, huh?
你就呆在栅栏那边，听到了吗?
You just stay on that side of that fence, you hear?
就在那边!
Right on that side over there!
来自辛迪加种植园的人，白人和黑人混在一起，戴着草帽，穿着胶靴，朝虎尾河口走去。
Men from the Syndicate Plantation, white and black mixed, headed for Tiger Tail bayou with straw gigs and rubber boots on.
我只希望他们转向下游。
I just hope they turn downstream.
我只希望他们擅闯我的地盘。
I just hope they trespass across my property.
我希望他们敢。
I hope they dare.
我会用猎枪把他们轰出河口。
I'll blast them out of the bayou with a shotgun.
小狗叫得很响。
Small dogs have a loud bark.
没人能侮辱我的女人。
Well, no one's gonna insult no woman of mine.
当你说我的时候，你把很多事情都当成了理所当然。
You take a lot for granted when you say mine.
我今天来找你寻求保护，我得到了什么?
I came to you today for protection and what did I get?
打了。被送回家。
Slapped. Sent home.
现在我告诉你，我们之间的协议结束了。
Now I'm tellin' you that the agreement between us is over.
你该死的，一切都结束了。
You darn tootin' it's over.
再过3个小时，3个小时，我们的协议条款就会敲定。
In just three hours, three hours, the terms of our agreement will be settled for good.
-别指望了。-午夜时分。
- Don't count on it. - Sharp at midnight.
最近这里发生的事太多了。
Too much has happened here lately.
我的信用卡又大开了。
Well, my credit is wide open again.
如果真相大白，监狱的大门也会关上。
And so is the jailhouse door if the truth comes out.
你是在用黑色威胁我吗?嗨!,席尔瓦!
Are you threatenin' me with black... Heigh-ho, Silva!
阿奇·李，瓦卡罗先生说他可能不会买一台新的轧棉机但可能会让你一直为他轧棉。
Archie Lee, Mr. Vacarro says that he might not put up a new cotton gin but might let you gin out his cotton for him all the time.
你不高兴吗?
Ain't you pleased about that?
他明天会带更多的棉花来。
He's gonna come tomorrow with lots more cotton.
在你发泄的时候，他会让我招待他。
And while you're ginnin' it out, he's gonna have me entertain him.
给他做柠檬水。
Make lemonade for him.
而且还会没完没了。甚至可能到明年秋天。
And it's gonna go on and on. Maybe even till next fall.
这是实际的睦邻政策。
It's the good neighbor policy in practice.
哦!
Oh!
你在这里多久了?
How long you been on the place?
整个漫长的秋天下午，都是我自找的。
All this unusually long fall afternoon, I've imposed on your hospitality.
你来过哪里?
Where you been here?
在你唯一剩下的床上打个盹。
Taking a nap on your only remainin' bed.
育婴室里放下板条的婴儿床。
The crib in the nursery with the slats let down.
有些悲伤，懂我的意思吗?
Something sad about it, know what I mean?
伤心什么?
Sad about what?
空房:房子里没有人住的育婴室，其他房间都是空的
An unoccupied nursery in a house and all the other rooms empty.
那不关你的事。
That's no problem of yours.
睦邻政策使你的问题成为我的问题，反之亦然。
The good neighbor policy makes your problems mine and vice-versa.
晚饭准备好了，孩子们。
Supper ready, children.
你们没听见我们被叫去吃晚饭吗?
Well, didn't you all hear us called in to supper?
你今晚要在这里吃吗?
You're gonna eat here tonight?
梅根太太让我留下来吃晚饭。
Oh, Mrs. Meighan asked me to stay for supper.
但我告诉她，在我接受邀请之前，我最好先听听户主的邀请。
But I told her I better get to hear the invitation from the head of the house before I'd feel free to accept it.
你怎么看?
So what do you say?
留下来吃晚饭。
Stay for supper.
好吧，你只能碰碰运气了。
Well, you'll have to take pot luck.
我不会打扰你吧?
I wouldn't be putting you out?
哦。不好意思，我得去换衣服了。
Oh. Excuse me, I better get into my clothes.
是啊，你最好这样。
Oh, yeah, you better.
我明白你的意思了吗?,嗯…你不愿意造一个新的杜松子酒却把你的生意留给我?
Did I understand you to say that... that, uh... you wouldn't build a new gin but would leave your business to me?
-如果你同意的话…-我不知道。
- If that's agreeable with you... - I don't know about that.
嗯，我得考虑一下这件事。
Well, I've got to consider the matter.
涉及到资金，比如新设备和……和…我们现在进去吃饭吧。
Financing is involved, such as new equipment and... and... Let's go in and eat now.
我肚子疼。我得到了……我有点…胃灼热。
I got a pain in the belly. I got... I got a sort of... heartburn.
嘿。
Hey.
嘿!又多了一个席位。
Hey! One more place at the table.
辛迪加种植园的瓦卡罗先生留下来吃晚饭。
Mr. Vacarro from the Syndicate Plantation is staying for supper.
我不知道会有人来。
I had no idea company was expected.
现在让我换衣服……另一个地方就够了。
Now just let me change... Another place is all that's called for.
你一整天都在这里吗?——嗯?
- Have you been here all day? - Huh?
你整个下午都在家还是去县医院吃巧克力糖了?
Have you been in the house all afternoon or did you ride out to the county hospital to eat some more chocolate candy?
是的，我去医院看望了一位朋友。
Yes, I visited a friend in the hospital.
然后你出去了，而我…我拼命地工作!
Then you were out while I... I worked like the hammers of hell!
我回到家，发现阁楼的地板塌下来了，我妻子脾气暴躁，还在侮辱人，晚餐是猪粪!
I come home to find the attic floor has fell through, my wife bad-tempered and insultin', and a supper of hog slops!
我想你有……
I suppose you've got...
坐下来。我得打个电话。
Sit down. I've gotta make me a phone call.
你好。我要"亮点"霍普金斯小姐。
Hello. I want the Bright Spot, Miss Hopkins.
把亮点给我。
Give me the Bright Spot.
我想不起数字了。现在给我，听到了吗?
I can't think of the number. Now you give it to me, you hear?
你好，亮点?
Hello, Bright Spot?
他在打电话。
He's on the phone about somethin'.
如果我是你，我就不会闲逛……我口袋里有张黑桃a我也要让他在上面签名。
If I was you, I wouldn't hang around... I've got the ace of spades in my pocket and I'm gonna get his autograph on it too.
哦，别指望法庭的法律。
Oh, don't count on the law of court.
这里的正义就像那个老妇人一样又聋又瞎。
Justice here is deaf and blind as that old woman.
我做我自己的事。
I do my own justice.
叫艾迪，比尔，布茨，罗兹，他们中的任何一个。
Get Eddie, Bill, Boots, Rhodes, anyone of them.
我建议你，趁他还在打电话，赶紧走。
I'm advising you, go while he's on the phone.
你不了解他的朋友。他们……他们是可怕的。
You don't know his friends. They're... they're awful.
我见过他们。
I've seen them.
我发现你今晚有些不一样。
I find you different this evenin' in some way.
没关系。
Never mind that.
趁他还在打电话，快走吧。
Just go while he's still on the phone.
突然长大了。
Grown up suddenly.
我平生第一次感到凉爽和放松。
I feel cool and rested for the first time in my life.
这就是我的感受。
That's the way I feel.
休息好了，凉快了。
Rested and cool.
现在他在这个县无处可逃了。
Now there's no place he can run to in this county.
嗯。你说得对，孩子。
Hmm. Well, you can say that again, boy.
是的。嗯哼。
Yeah. Mm-hmm.
如果你不能离开，那就派人来。
If you can't leave the place, then you send someone.
但你派人去找他，听到了吗?
But you send someone to find him, you hear me?
我再打给你。
I'll call you back.
自然之诗。如果我有……不要在意大自然的诗。
Poems of nature. If I had... Never mind the poems of nature.
再见。我一会儿打给你。
Goodbye. I'll call you later.
早知道有人陪我就好了。
If I'd only known company was expected.
-把食物放在桌子上。-稍等一下。
- Put some food on the table. - Just take a minute.
我们不会再等了。
We ain't gonna wait no minute.
拿些吃的出来!
Bring out some food!
这就是他们所说的…你这是蒙娜丽莎式的微笑吗，小猫咪?
Is that what they call a... a Mona Lisa smile you got on you, puss?
把食物放在桌子上!
Put some food on the table!
别挑玫瑰阿姨的毛病。
Don't pick on Aunt Rose Comfort.
今晚我要和那个老太太好好谈谈。
I'm gonna have a talk with that old woman right here tonight.
她待得太久了。
She's outstayed her welcome.
你今晚戴的蓝丝带真漂亮，梅根太太。
What a pretty blue ribbon you're wearing tonight, Mrs. Meighan.
谢谢你，瓦卡罗先生。
Why, thank you, Mr. Vacarro.
蓝色有那么多深浅。
There's so many shades of blue.
那是什么颜色?
What particular shade is that?
它是浅蓝色的。
It's just baby blue.
衬托出你蓝色的眼睛。
Brings out the blue of your eyes.
食物!
Food!
——食品!-马上，马上。
- Food! - Immediately, this instant.
这件毛衣是我嫁妆的一部分。
This sweater was part of my trousseau.
我所有的嫁妆都是在我爸爸出名的孟菲斯的百货公司买的。
I got all my trousseau at various department stores in Memphis where my daddy was known.
-这是什么东西?草?-是绿色的。
- What is this stuff? Grass? - It's greens.
难道你看不出绿色吗?
Don't you know greens when you see them?
主街上的大百货商店……这东西是绿色的吗?
Big department stores on Main Street... This stuff is greens?
阿奇·李特别喜欢吃绿色蔬菜。
Archie Lee dotes on greens.
-是吗，阿奇·李?-不，我没有。
- Don't you, Archie Lee? - No, I don't.
你不?你不喜欢吃绿色蔬菜?
You don't? You don't dote on greens?
好吧，有人这么做了。
Well, somebody did.
也许有人在某个时候，某个地方干过，但那不代表是我干的。
Somebody probably did sometime, somewhere, but that don't mean it was me.
吃你的绿色蔬菜，大人物。绿色植物能增加血液中的铁元素。
Eat your greens, bigshot. Greens put iron in the blood.
我以为阿奇·李很喜欢吃蔬菜。
I thought Archie Lee doted on greens.
所有这些好恶很难在你的脑海中保持清晰，但阿奇·李(Archie Lee)很容易做饭。
All these likes and dislikes are hard to keep straight in your head, but Archie Lee is easy to cook for.
把桌子上的泔水拿掉。
Take this slop off the table.
我在伯明翰给你煮些鸡蛋。
I'll cook you some eggs Birmingham.
这些蔬菜没煮熟。
These greens didn't cook enough.
我对我的炉子开了个愚蠢的玩笑。
I played a fool trick with my stove.
我…我忘了点灯了。
I... I forgot to light it.
当我去商店的时候，我把绿色蔬菜留在炉子上了。
When I went out to the store, I left my greens on the stove.
我以为他们在沸腾。
I thought they were boilin'.
当我回到家时，我发现我的炉子还没点上。
When I came home, I discovered my stove wasn't lit.
你为什么说我的炉子?
Why do you say my stove?
为什么一切都是我的，我的，我的……阿奇·李，我想你喝多了。
Why is everything mine, mine, mine... Archie Lee, I think you've been drinkin'.
你别插手。坐下，罗斯阿姨。
You stay out of this. Sit down, Aunt Rose.
-那是什么，阿奇·李?-坐下。
- What was that, Archie Lee? - Sit down.
在哪里?
Where?
坐下来。
Sit down.
我要问你一个问题。
I'm gonna ask you a question.
你有什么计划?
What sort of plans have you made?
什么计划，阿奇·李?你指的是什么样的计划?
What plans, Archie Lee? What sort of plans do you mean?
对未来的计划。
Plans for the future.
阿奇·李，我觉得没必要在众人面前讨论这个问题。
Archie Lee, I don't think this discussion is necessary in front of company.
梅根太太，当一个人对某件事感到不舒服时，他通常会把他的烦恼发泄在一些完全无辜的人身上。
Mrs. Meighan, when someone feels uncomfortable over somethin', it often happens he takes out his annoyance on some completely innocent person.
露丝阿姨，你八月就来了。
Now, Aunt Rose, you've been here since August.
那可真够久的。
That's a mighty long stay.
老实说，我认为你需要休息一下。
And it's my honest opinion that you're in need of a rest.
你在这里和那里都做了多久了?
You've been cooking around here and cooking around there for how long now?
好吗?
Well?
你在别人家做饭有多久了?
How long you been cooking around people's houses?
我帮助我的亲戚，我的家人，只要他们需要我。
I helped out my relatives, my folks, whenever they needed me.
我总是受到邀请，有时还乞求我来。
I was always invited, sometimes begged to come.
当有孩子或有人生病时，他们就叫罗丝阿姨，而罗丝阿姨总是准备好了。
When babies was expected or somebody was sick, they called for Aunt Rose and Aunt Rose was always ready.
从来没人逼我出去。
Nobody ever had to put me out.
先生们，我离开餐桌好吗?我…
Will you gentlemen excuse me from the dinner table? I...
我去收拾行李。
I'll run up and pack.
罗丝小姐，等等。
Miss Rose Comfort, wait.
我开车送你回家。
I'll drive you home.
我没有地方可去。
I don't have nowhere to go.
是的，你需要。我需要一个厨师。
Yes, you do. I need a cook.
我已经厌倦了自己做的菜，我很想尝尝你提到的伯明翰鸡蛋。
I'm tired of my own cooking and I'm anxious to try those eggs Birmingham you mentioned.
成交了吗?
Is it a deal?
嗯…当然，一言为定，萝丝阿姨。
Well... Oh, sure, it's a deal, Aunt Rose.
瓦卡罗先生会对你很好的。
Mr. Vacarro will be very good to you.
未来的事情你永远也说不准。
And you never can tell about things in the future.
是的。我要收拾东西了。
Yeah. I'm gonna pack my things.
宝贝，请不要走
* Baby please don't go *
不要去…?＊
* Don't go...? *
这里还有什么你想带走的吗，瓦卡罗先生?
Is there anything else around here you wanna take away with you, Mr. Vacarro?
嗯，有吗?
Well, is there?
是的，阿奇·李。
Why, yes, Archie Lee.
瓦卡罗先生注意到房子里全是家具，他想借五套完整的家具。
Mr. Vacarro noticed that the house was just full of furniture and he'd like to borrow about five complete sets of it.
嗯。
Mmm.
有色人种把这叫做烈酒。
Colored folks call this pot liquor.
哦。
Oh.
-我喜欢烈酒。——嗯?
- I love pot liquor. - Hmm?
好吗?
Good?
我对大麻酒很着迷。
I'm crazy about pot liquor.
嗯。嗯。嗯。
Mmm. Mmm. Mmm.
-很好。-嗯，好吃吗?
- It's good. - Mmm, is it good?
——唔唔。——嗯。
- Mm-mmm. - Mmm.
——好。-很好。嗯。
- Good. - That's good. Mmm.
那只老母鸡走了进来，好像有人请她吃晚饭似的。
That old hen was comin' in like she'd been invited to supper.
嘎嘎，嘎嘎，嘎嘎，嘎嘎。
Quack, quack, quack, quack.
你听我说!现在你们都听我说。
You listen to me! Now you all listen to me.
现在，别再用那种肮脏的眼神来来回回地看我，听我说。
Now you quit giving those filthy looks back and forth and listen to me.
怎么，你以为我又聋又哑又瞎，是吗?
Why, you think I'm deaf, dumb and blind or something, do you?
好吧，你错了。
Well, you're mistook.
哦,哥哥。
Oh, brother.
哦，兄弟，但你大错特错了。
Oh, brother, but you're much, much mistook.
我知道。
I know.
我知道，我想我看起来像…一个……一个……我想我看起来像个…你觉得你长得像什么，阿奇·李?
I know, I guess I look like a... a... a... I guess I look like a... What do you guess you look like, Archie Lee?
是啊，一个可爱，天真的娇妻?
Yes, some sweet, little, innocent baby doll of a wife, huh?
还没准备好结婚，是吧?
Oh, not ready for marriage, huh?
哦，不，还没准备好结婚，但已经准备好和他约会了……等一下。我知道这有多好笑了。
Oh, no, not ready for marriage, but plenty ready to go out with him and... Wait a minute now. I see how it's funny.
很有趣，不是吗?
It sure is funny, isn't it, huh?
你忽略了一件非常非常小的事情。
There's one little teensy-weensy thing that you've overlooked.
我有位置了。
I got position.
我在我出生和长大的这个县找到了一个职位。
I got position in this county where I was born and brought up.
-别说了!-我身居高位!
- Stop it! - I hold a respected position!
三角洲所有组织的终身会员!
Lifelong member of every organization in the delta!
站在我这边的是朋友!
On my side are friends!
朋友们!
Friends!
长期的商业伙伴和社会伙伴。
Long-standin' business associates and social.
你明白我的意思了吧?
You see what I mean, huh?
你没有这个优势，对吧，先生?
You ain't got that advantage, have you, mister?
你有吗?有你吗?
Well, have you, huh? Have you?
来吧，说出来。嗯?
Come on, speak up. Huh?
你不是意大利佬吗?
Ain't you a dago or somethin'?
打扰一下。我是说意大利菜之类的……我不是医生，但我曾是海军医疗队的一员。
Excuse me. I mean Italian or somethin'... I'm not a doctor, but I was a medical corps in the navy.
你看起来很不健康。
You've got a very unhealthy look.
叫救护车…我甚至不需要打个电话。
And call an ambulance... I don't even have to make a phone call.
我自己能处理好。
I can handle the situation myself.
你指的是什么情况?
What situation do you mean?
我回家后在我的屋檐下发现的情况!
Situation which I come home to find here under my roof!
哦，看这里。
Oh, look here now.
哦，我不是那种…我真是个缺弹珠的老傻瓜，根本无法估量。
Oh, I'm not such a... Such a marble-missing old fool I couldn't size it up.
当我看到你还在这里的时候我就估量了哦，她，她脸上带着狡黠的微笑，你脸上带着你的微笑。
I sized it up the minute I seen you were still on this place and her... Oh, her, her with that sly smile on her and you with yours on you.
我知道怎么抹去这两个狡黠的笑容……Meighan !
Well, I know how to wipe off both those sly smiles... Meighan!
你知道，我知道，我知道你知道我知道你昨晚放火烧了我的轧棉机。
You know, and I know, and I know that you know that I know that you set fire to my cotton gin last night.
你烧了辛迪加的杜松子酒而我手上有一份签字的宣誓书，一份由证人签字的文件他的证词在虎尾县的法庭上也站得住脚。
You burned down the Syndicate gin and I got here in my hand a signed affidavit, a paper signed by a witness whose testimony will hold up even in the law courts of Tiger Tail county.
这就是我来这里的目的，这就是我所拥有的一切。
That's what I come here for and that's all I got.
不管你还有什么…你怀疑，嗯，你错了。
Whatever else you... you suspect, well, you're mistaken.
不是吗，梅根太太?
Isn't that so, Mrs. Meighan?
难道你丈夫认为
Isn't your husband mistaken in thinkin'
我从这里得到了什么除了这份签字的宣誓书那就是我打了一下午电话的目的?
I got anything out of this place but this signed affidavit which was the purpose of my all-afternoon call?
我是外国人，梅根，但我没有复仇心。
I'm foreign, Meighan, but not revengeful.
至少不会超过应有的限度。
At least not more than is rightful.
现在我们之间有了可行的睦邻政策。
Now we got a workable good neighbor policy between us.
可能会成功。
It might work out.
无论如何，我认为它值得一试。
Anyhow, I think it deserves a try.
至于另一方面，我就不提了，我只能说存在某种吸引力。
Now as to the other side of the situation which I won't mention, well, all I can say is a certain attraction exists.
我相信是相互的。
Mutually, I believe.
昨晚的兴奋过后，我需要睡一会儿，我隐约记得有人给我唱过歌。
I needed a little shut-eye after last night's excitement and I have a faint recollection of being sung to by someone.
一首甜美的摇篮曲，冰凉的手指轻轻触碰。
A lullaby song that was sweet and the touch of cool fingers.
-你觉得我会…-但仅此而已，绝对的。
- You think I'm gonna... - But that's all, absolutely.
-你以为我会把…-这种情况?
- You think I'm gonna put up... - With this situation?
你冒了这么大的风险和麻烦才把我的生意抢回来。
You went to a whole lot of risk and trouble to get my business back.
——酷。-现在你不想要了吗?
- Cool. - Now don't you want it?
-是啊，很酷。-由你决定，阿奇·李
- Yeah, cool. - It's up to you, Archie Lee.
-哦，太酷了。-由你决定。
- Oh, very cool. - It's up to you.
-你刚修好你的马车。-是的。
- You just fixed your wagon. - Yeah.
说了这么聪明的话，你的马车就修好了。
With this smart talk, oh, you just fixed your wagon.
我要让你那张油腻的德国佬脸上的笑容永远消失。
I'm gonna wipe that grin off your greasy wop face for good.
哦，你只是…你的手表。
Oh, you just... you watch.
我的德国脸油腻吗，梅根太太?
Is my wop face greasy, Mrs. Meighan?
Vacarro !
Vacarro!
这是你最后一次碰我，你这个臭家伙!
That's the last time you're ever gonna lay your hands on me, you stinking stinker!
你这个臭家伙。臭鬼!
You stinking stinker. Stinker!
小心，席尔瓦!
Look out, Silva!
岩石。
Rock.
洛克，你在哪里?
Rock, where are you?
你在哪，瓦卡罗?你在哪里?
Where are you, Vacarro? Where are you?
你躲在哪里，小子?
Where you hiding, wop?
如果你在下面，你就出不去了。
Oh, if you're under there, you ain't getting out.
我丈夫有枪，而我不…
My husband's got a gun and I just don't...
嘿,wop !哦，你这个胆小鬼。
Hey, wop! Oh, you yellow-bellied wop.
把枪拿来!把枪从他身上拿开!
Get that gun! Get that gun away from him!
的帮助!的帮助!
Help! Help!
离我远点!
Get away from me!
得到……离开!
Get... get away!
你在哪，瓦卡罗?
Where are you, Vacarro?
就在这里，邻居。
Right here, neighbor.
啊!哦，你在这儿。
Ah! Oh, there you are.
哦。哦，是你。
Oh. Oh, it's you.
原谅我。
Excuse me.
-席尔瓦。——嘘。嘘。这里。
- Silva. - Psst. Psst. Here.
-你在哪里?——在这里。
- Where are you? - Here.
你在哪，瓦卡罗?
Where are you, Vacarro?
-来吧。-哦，哦，哦，哦。
- Come on. - Oh, oh, oh, ow, ow.
——哦吼!-宝贝娃娃!
- Woohoo! - Baby Doll!
你在哪，瓦卡罗?
Where are you, Vacarro?
Vacarro。
Vacarro.
Vacarro !
Vacarro!
出来吧!
Come on out!
出来吧，瓦卡罗!
Come on out, Vacarro!
啊!把你的枪收起来。
Ah! Now you put that gun of yours away.
娃娃!
Baby Doll!
宝宝……娃娃。
Baby... Baby Doll.
洋娃娃。
Doll.
娃娃。
Baby Doll.
哦，瓦卡罗，在哪里…你在哪里，你…wop吗?
Oh, Vacarro, where... Where are you, you... you wop?
宝宝……
Baby...
洋娃娃。
Doll.
娃娃。
Baby Doll.
哦，我的宝贝娃娃。
Oh, my Baby Doll.
不，不，不。
No, no, no, no.
娃娃。
Baby Doll.
我准备好了。都准备好了。
I'm ready. All ready to go.
那是谁?
Now who is that?
怎么了，桑迪?出什么事了吗?
What's the matter, Sandy? Is something wrong?
明天就是选举日我要竞选镇警长这是我第25次竞选我希望你们投我一票。
Tomorrow's election day and I'm running for town marshal for the 25th time and I want your vote.
-我投你一票，桑迪。-让我看看你的枪，伙计
- You got my vote, Sandy. - Let me see you gun, fella.
——我……-来，让我看看你的枪。
- I... - Come on, let's see your gun.
是啊，你太老了，不适合干这种活。
Yeah, doggone, man, you're too old for a job like that.
我比你年轻20岁，我不会去竞选那样的工作。
I'm 20 years younger than you and I wouldn't run for a job like that.
你知道年龄是一个需要认可的因素。
You know that age is a factor calls for recognition.
我希望你能认识到它需要认可的事实。
I hope you recognize the fact it calls for recognition.
你知道的…人会突然变老，不是慢慢变老的。
You know... a man grows old suddenly, not gradual.
突然之间，他老了。
Just all of a sudden, he's old.
等等，你们要带我去哪?
Hey, now wait a minute, where are you guys taking me?
你表现得好像我被捕了似的。
You're acting as though I'm under arrest or somethin'.
-你一直在射击…-他来了。
- Well, you've been shootin'... - There he is.
哦,不。不!
Oh, no. No!
放开我。放开我。
Get off me. Get off me.
嘿，那我呢?
Hey, how about me?
给他戴上手铐。
Put the handcuffs on him.
好的。好的。
Okay. Okay.
把我放进…那个发臭的黑葫芦。
Put me in that... that stinking black calaboose.
我不是白人?不，我不是白人，把我扔进去吧。
I ain't a white man? No, I ain't a white man so throw me in.
但别把我的宝贝娃娃留给他。
But don't you leave my Baby Doll here with him.
别把他留在这里和她在一起。
Don't you leave him here with her.
桑迪，听着，你是个已婚男人。
Sandy, listen, you're a married man.
你能理解我的感受。不是吗，桑迪?
You understand how I feel. Don't you, Sandy?
请为…作为一个白人对另一个白人，就今晚，不要把他留在原地。
Please, as... as one white man to another, just for tonight, don't leave him on the place.
就今晚，桑迪。
Just tonight, Sandy.
哦。
Oh.
我的腿被那棵树皮划伤了。
I've scratched my leg on the bark of that tree.
瓦卡罗，过来。
Vacarro, come here.
原谅我。
Excuse me.
现在你在想什么?
Now what you got on your mind?
听着，伙计，我们一无所有
Listen, fella, we ain't got nothin'
留住那个老男孩。
to hold that old boy on.
他一直在院子里扫射，但他告诉我们有个坏蛋在抓他的鸡。
He's been shootin' up his yard a little, but he tells us a varmint's been catchin' his chickens.
他的鸡吗?我有一份重要证人签署的认罪书，相当于一份宣誓书。
His chickens? I've got a signed confession by a material witness that amounts to an affidavit.
除非有人目睹并拍照。
Not till it's witnessed by others and Photostated.
我们会找人见证并拍照…我不需要你的任何东西。
We'll have it witnessed and photographed... I don't need anything from you.
我不想要你的任何东西。
I don't want anything from you.
我要去找县警长。
I'm going to the county sheriff.
摇滚!
Rock!
在这里,席尔瓦。
Here, Silva.
这里!
Here!
但是，席尔瓦，那我呢?
But, hey, Silva, how about me?
现在?
Now?
我明天会带更多的棉花回来!
I'll be coming back tomorrow with lots more cotton!
I'll be back tomorrow with lots more cotton!
-他走了。-现在怎么办?
- Well, he's gone. - What happens now?
他果然拿到了你妻子签字的认罪书。
Well, he sure enough got hisself a signed confession from your wife.
现在为了面子，我们得把这事过一遍。
Now we're gonna have to go through this thing for appearance's sake.
我不是那个意思。我的意思是……
I don't mean that. I mean...
明天会发生什么?
what happens tomorrow?
镇法警管不了明天的事。
Well, the town marshal has no control over tomorrow.
今天是我宝贝娃娃的生日。
Today is my Baby Doll's birthday.
你的朋友忘了我。
Your friend forgot me.
阿奇·李，看来庆祝结束了。
Well, Archie Lee, it looks like the celebration is over.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
他明天会带更多的棉花回来。
He's coming back tomorrow with more cotton.
他要回来了?
He's coming back?
哦，好吧，我们现在进去吧。
Oh, well, let's go in now.
我们无事可做，只能等到明天……看看我们会不会被记住……或被遗忘。
We got nothin' to do, but wait for tomorrow... and see if we are remembered... or forgotten.